Chapter 63

A Visit to the Resident Mad Scientist

Jake really had to restrain himself every time he visited Arnold. Mainly by suppressing his desire to see if he could break through the big dome of metal that guarded his workshop. It looked and felt damn sturdy, but he should have a good shot with enough destructive arcane mana. If not, then surely Touch of the Malefic could do it.

Alas, he was not there to break stuff.

He had already gone to see Arnold before he went on holiday, so he was a bit interested in why Arnold had asked for him to stop by. Interested in what kind of thing the madman had made that he wanted to show Jake and potentially hand him. Or maybe he wanted a favor this time around?

As expected, he was let straight in, as Arnold was aware Jake was back. The workshop had expanded once more, this time primarily downwards, it seemed. From Jake’s sphere, he also saw some weird robot-looking things digging even further, making it clear the scientist was still expanding.

It didn’t take long to locate Arnold, who was working inside a laboratory with a familiar cube. The one Jake had brought from the Void God, Oras.

"Good, you are here," Arnold stated when Jake entered without even turning around.

Jake was a bit surprised—not by what he was doing, but by the response when he used Identify on the man.

[Human – lvl 199]

The bastard has surpassed Jake in level. As for if he was working on getting his Perfect Evolution or still had evolution quests to finish, Jake didn’t know, but he had still surpassed Jake. Holidays were truly detrimental to growth.

"So, what did you want?" Jake asked bluntly.

"I have been made aware you will soon return to the Order of the Malefic Viper," Arnold stated. "I would ask of you to procure some materials when you are there. Compensation shall naturally follow. Further discussion as to the form of compensation beyond Credits is possible."

"Oh?" Jake asked, surprised, but he quickly got it. Arnold was probably running low on high-level materials. The guy had stockpiled when the System Store was around and made ample use of the Holy Church and all other merchant groups… but by now, he had outgrown them. That, or they were gone off the planet.

Maybe he even needed them for his evolution quest.

"Sure, we can figure something out," Jake agreed.

Arnold nodded and took out a tablet from his spatial storage, then handed it to Jake. "All details are within. A list has been made and ordered based on priority. Will a deposit of funds for the purchase be necessary?"

"Nah, I should be able to front the cash." Jake shrugged as he took the tablet and opened it to see the… list. He started scrolling. It kept going. "Arnold… how many items are there?"

"Eight hundred and seventy-one unique entries, the quantity of each item specified individually," Arnold answered with a deadpan face.

Poor Meira, Jake could only think as he put the tablet in his inventory.

"This is quite a lot," Jake commented. "And even if I don’t want a deposit now… maybe we can talk about what you can potentially offer."

Arnold looked at Jake for a moment. "I would advise delaying. Preparations are underway for projects designated for use by C-grades. Based on the assumption that you are close to evolution, I predict any items would be more useful for you then. Moreover, the items requested have a high likelihood of including the materials required for these projects. Before knowing what is possible to acquire, I cannot give an offer."

"Eh… sounds logic," Jake said. He would need a lot of new stuff after his evolution, wouldn’t he? "But give me a sneak peek anyway, okay? Come on. You must have something fun in the works."

The man took a moment before nodding. "Continued research has gone into improving many weapons. Follow me."

Jake gladly did so as they entered another workshop. Walking to a wall, Arnold activated some magic that rapidly removed the barriers. Jake had already seen the hidden room behind the wall and also knew that he had no fucking way to enter it. The way it was hidden was actually damn smart.

The walls that enclosed the room were three or so meters thick and made of metal, very similar to what the dome consisted of. It would take quite a while to get through it, and Jake reckoned only Alchemical Flame could do the job. The opening mechanism to enter was also simple but effective. The door of sorts required one to open it correctly, or a massive wall of steel would fall and block the entrance—and from the looks of it, Arnold had placed bombs on the inside to blow it the hell up if anyone broke in. The dude was very dedicated to protecting his works in progress.

Entering the room, Jake saw a few interesting things.

The first was a golem that Jake very much recognized. In a tank filled with murky water, the Census Golem floated, nearly all the destruction on it restored, though by other types of metal. If it was functional, Jake didn’t know, but clearly Arnold was far from done with it.

Next up were a few gun-like things in cases. Or, well, calling them blasters was probably more accurate. Jake had no way to properly evaluate those, but they looked fancy. Besides that, there were many different kinds of drones and spherical robots of sorts beyond Jake’s understanding.

Arnold clearly knew this, which was why he led Jake to the one item Jake would likely care about. It was just a long, thin piece of metal, but Jake recognized it right away. It was a nanoblade.

"Further improvements of the nanoblade are in progress, the durability, sharpness, and mana conductivity improving continuously,” Arnold said. “Seeing your recent switch to the use of katars, time will be needed to optimize the internal structure to support thrusting over slashing attacks. Moreover, from your explanations of Fangs of the Malefic Viper, the nanoblade can be further optimized to better facilitate and make use of the skill. I assume you are still interested in the weapon?"

Jake looked at it for a bit before nodding. While he had two weapons right now, he knew the bone weapon was only temporary. When sim-Jake fully merged with him, it would lose much of its Records and power, making it effectively useless. By then, he would need another katar anyway.

Arnold took out his usual tablet and noted down this answer. "Finally, I recall you are planning on visiting the Grand Mangrove River. If possible, please take this along with you."

The man summoned a weird-looking cylinder of metal about the size of a person. Jake saw that on the inside, it was filled with mechanisms. He could only throw Arnold a questioning look.

"The spatial mana within the Grand Mangrove River has interesting properties,” Arnold explained. “I would like to analyze it to assist in another project of mine. From my initial tests, while a satellite is easily doable, proper drones for space exploration face challenges in the open cosmos, as creatures and energies now lurk there. From my assessment, the Grand Mangrove River’s spatial mana has natural properties related to the concept of stealth.”

Jake simply nodded and took the cylinder. "Makes sense."

He had noticed the energy there before, of course. He had not quite identified it as some stealth concept, but then again, maybe it was a mix of space and stealth. Either way, what it truly was and how to make use of it was for Arnold to figure out.

"Anywhere specific you want it placed?" He asked to follow up.

"Somewhere safe, as the measuring device is not made to sustain unnecessary and sudden forces acting upon it during readings," Arnold answered. "Simply place it somewhere and infuse mana into the center circle. That will allow me to know it is in position and remotely activate it."

"Got it," Jake confirmed. As he stood there, he couldn’t help but notice the many robots flying everywhere within his sphere throughout the workshop, especially those that seemed to do some rather complicated work, like analyzing what looked like circuit boards. So he couldn’t help but ask, "Say, how do you even manage to control all these drones of yours? Even back in the Treasure Hunt, you had so many flying around. Are they all programmed? Some kind of artificial intelligence?"

It was a little rude to ask about someone’s secrets like that, but considering how much Jake had shared with the man, he thought it okay to ask.

Arnold seemed a bit surprised by the question but was in no way offended. No, it was the exact opposite… He seemed elated that Jake had asked, giving Jake a bad feeling. A feeling that only grew as Arnold lowered his tablet and seemed to dedicate his whole attention to Jake.

"A number of methods have been applied. Most mundane models still run on simple programming, while more advanced models make use of artificial soul constructs. The Altmar Census Golem was my basis for these constructs, and I can only admire their ingenuity and prowess. However, the methodology and magiscripts used by the Altmar Empire do not suit my own, requiring me to adapt it, which made me switch to a more unorthodox approach by applying scripts and runes of the eldritch variety.

“The skill I received from Oras allows me to more easily split my attention between different tasks, and by augmenting the concepts within, I managed to implement soul constructs faintly mimicking my own, which then also allows me to temporarily fully immerse a part of my consciousness within a given model. Do note that I do not need to use this functionality, as the artificial soul construct will already act based on preprogrammed instructions and can be updated remotely through the eldritch scripts. Finally, all information from every drone is fed to me continuously, which required me to develop skills and methods to filter, archive, and, in other ways, sort through all data gathered. Models of machine learning are being applied here, which do require further development and improvement of skills, but the prospects are promising. If you are interested in delving into some examples of this theory, I could show you—"

"No, I’m good," Jake cut him off.

Okay, he had gotten way more than he had bitten off, and it did sound interesting, but more the kind of interesting that Casper would be excited about. Sure, Jake understood what Arnold meant, but he also understood that Arnold was doing something others simply couldn’t. From how he understood it, Arnold effectively split his mind into segments and had each handle different things. At least partly. Of course, this wasn’t really anything special, and in fact, it was considered kind of normal to do this. Jake could, as an example, focus on different things at once while doing alchemy or using magic, but Arnold had taken it to a whole new level for a D-grade. One could only imagine how much more extreme it would become when he reached C-grade.

"Have you faced any issues with different personas emerging or conflicting thoughts?" Jake did have to ask, as he knew that was a risk. Especially as he was dealing with someone using the Legacy of a Void God. Eldritch things and human brains didn’t mesh well, based on all the books Jake had read pre-system.

"No," Arnold simply answered.

"Well, geez," Jake joked, having expected him to at least admit he had some problems. "Did you make a legendary skill or something to not mess with your head?"

"The initial skill received by Oras was at legendary rarity," Arnold confirmed, making Jake feel a bit better… at least until the next sentence. "However, I only became able to properly create my artificial soul constructs who were able to act autonomously after the upgrade to mythical rarity."

Jake was taken aback. "You created a mythical skill?"

Arnold, even more surprisingly, shook his head. "No, not truly. Due to its nature as a Legacy skill, I did not upgrade my title from the achievement due to the offered Records and assistance from Oras."

That at least made Jake feel a bit better, and he even felt some relief from within his Soulspace, as sim-Jake was also looking on.

"Well, either way, damn if it isn’t impressive,” Jake said. “Say, you pretty much put a part of your soul into each of these machines, right?"

"No, that assessment is incorrect. My soul remains intact and singular. However, partitions are linked through void scripts to each model.”

Jake nodded. "I see. Well, this has been very enlightening, but if there isn’t more, I should be on my way."

"Very well," Arnold answered, looking a bit disappointed before leading Jake out of the hidden room with all his interesting works in progress.

Jake said his goodbyes and quickly headed out toward the teleporter. On his way, he had to admit… he felt a tad relieved.

The reason for that last question was actually pretty simple. He wanted to probe if Arnold had delved into soul magic, or what people often called soul ritualism. Jake had already done some soul magic himself, but he wanted to see if Arnold had begun to delve into actually altering his own soul. Mixing eldritch magic and soul magic couldn’t be good, in Jake’s eyes, and also, there was one final reason.

He wanted to know if Arnold planned on staying human. From how Jake saw it, Arnold was a prime candidate for someone to evolve out of their usual human form, maybe even turning himself into a robot or sentient computer or some shit.

However, this was not necessarily a smart thing to do. Arnold was still human, no matter how weird he was, and still had many of the more positive traits of humanity, such as emotions. Arnold becoming a robot was a prime path to turning evil, especially with his Patron.

Jake could only imagine the horrors of a sentient eldritch supercomputer without any empathy or emotions. While it was entirely possible for Arnold to not go down this path even if he changed his form, it was a potential threat. At least it looked like Arnold was not planning anything like this, and would remain a living human supercomputer instead.

Shaking his head, Jake moved on to the next task at hand: visiting the Grand Mangrove River. He hadn’t been there since he traveled through with Carmen and Sylphie, but he had wanted to visit for a while, primarily to thank them for helping him out by protecting Miranda and the others when he couldn’t. Miranda had praised them a lot, especially the Crimsoneye Alabaster Snake who led the group. It was only right that Jake would go in person to show his gratitude and chat with them.

As he got close to the teleporter, he suddenly remembered something. Jake had a tendency to zone out during long, boring talks, but he did remember Miranda mentioning the name of the Crimsoneye Snake at some point…. He just couldn’t quite recall what she was called.

Oh, well. I can just ask her.

Jake also remembered Miranda mentioning that the snake had learned to take human form, so that was also interesting and definitely something he wanted to check out and talk to her about.

Chapter 64

Snake Friends Visit!

To call the settlement in the Grand Mangrove River a city wasn’t quite right. It was more of a small village, though it had been expanding in recent times, especially after the teleporter was installed. The reason for this was also quite obvious.

It was a prime hunting ground.

A settlement like this was rare, as one could teleport directly into a place with D-grades all around you while still being safe. One had to remember that only a handful of people on Earth could fight C-grades, and the vast majority thus still needed to hunt D-grades to progress. Even the people considered elite struggled with stronger D-grades.

Additionally, it was a great place for those with the wood or water affinity to fight. Finally, it had one other advantage that Jake hadn’t really considered: It was a place where C-grades could go if Jake wanted to meet with them there. Thinking about it deeper, it was probably the place Jake would meet with whatever final council member the King found.

All of this being possible was naturally due to a certain snake. A snake Jake was now on his way to meet once he felt done scouting out the village. It did have an interesting setup due to the environment, and there were quite a lot of people around, all of them pretty high-level D-grades. However, what he cared most about were two buildings.

The first of which was the largest building and a main office of sorts. The second one was a small but well-guarded building, which Jake noted led into a pit of sorts that ran deep inside the Grand Mangrove River’s water. Not sure which one to check out first, Jake went for the pit after sensing the aura from it.

By the way, although Jake said well-guarded, it wasn’t by any of the C-grades, but just two humans. There were also barriers that would no doubt make everyone aware if someone tried to break in, but none of that was an issue for Jake, as the guard recognized him and opened the entrance to the pit without a word.

As for why Jake wanted to explore the pit so badly? Because he felt a familiar aura from below. One that reminded him a lot of Chris’ monument, which had allowed him to teleport to the Order of the Malefic Viper…

Jake felt a flare-up of anger, but he quickly suppressed it before the guards even noticed and entered the pit.

I swear, that orange fuck is gonna get what he deserves, Jake said to himself as he began descending into the pit. It looked more like a deep well than anything else, and Jake didn’t hesitate to jump down and allow himself to freefall.

He fell for a bit over twenty seconds, putting the depth of the hole at around a kilometer. Upon landing, Jake found himself in a dug-out cavern with several tunnels leading away from it. He noticed that all of these tunnels had engravings on the walls and hummed with magic. Feeling curious, Jake began making his way through a tunnel, eventually finding that it led into another similar chamber, though without the entrance. Closing his eyes, Jake used his senses to get a feeling for the space.

It’s a magic circle, he swiftly concluded.

The pattern was far too purposeful and distinct for it to be anything else. Jake wondered if the creator was anywhere nearby, but he soon got his answer. A presence made its way through one of the tunnels, and Jake turned to face it. A long, brownish snake slithered in his direction, its size filling out nearly half of the tunnel, putting its diameter at nearly four meters. Jake guessed the beast had to be several hundred meters long, and its head was large enough to eat a human whole. Not that Jake felt any threat, as he recognized the snake as one of those who followed the Crimsoneye one.

"Hey, there," Jake greeted as the snake got close. It then did something utterly terrifying.

The face of the snake began warping. Bone cracked, flesh twisted, and a vaguely humanoid face straight out of a nightmare emerged, still on the body of the massive snake.

"Grrrreetingsss, Maeeelefic’sssss Chooossssennnn," the snake spoke, showing off the prowess of Jake’s translation skill by even allowing him to comprehend what the snake had said through the hissing.

"Good practice with the transformation, but how about we keep this conversation telepathic?" Jake offered. He really didn’t want to insult a snake that was clearly trying so hard.

Nearly instantly, the face warped back to the old snake visage, and a voice echoed in Jake’s mind. "Thank you for your permission to speak in this fashion; I am not as adept as the others in the art of human speech, and have neglected practice with the Polymorph skill."

"All good," Jake answered, happy to not look at the nightmare creature the snake had transformed into. He was also surprised at the telepathic voice of the snake. It sounded… old? Most beasts Jake spoke to telepathically sounded very young, but this snake sounded on the more mature side.

"Have you come looking for the mistress?" the snake asked.

"Partly. I also came to check out the work down here. Well, not specifically the work down here, as I didn’t know what it would look like, but it is quite impressive. Are you involved in making the magic circle?"

He had a feeling the snake was, for a few reasons. First of all, he faintly felt the space affinity from the snake. Secondly, it was down in the tunnel where the formation was being made, and lastly, it had a Blessing of the Malefic Viper.

"Yes, this one has been given the honor of creating this grand work of art. I thank the Chosen for this opportunity. I hope to do the task to the utmost of my abilities.” The large, brown snake spoke in an overly polite and submissive tone. He could try to convince the snake to treat him more normally, but it wasn’t worth it.

"From the looks of it, you are doing a splendid job," Jake said, praising the snake. "But I heard a part of the process requires my assistance; am I correct?"

"Such is the will of the Malefic One. The circle will need to be attuned and rely on the True Blessing of his Chosen so only he can teleport and decide who goes or not.”

"Great. What do you need of me and where? Please lead the way, and let’s get it solved right away."

"Please follow me, my Lord.”

The snake then did something Jake had not seen coming. It managed to turn around in the narrow tunnel, the space around it seeming to warp and twist. A second later, the snake had finished its one-eighty and began moving. Jake followed the old snake through the winding tunnel system of runes and magic. As he moved through, he did notice spots where his ritualism skill made him aware things were missing or unfinished, making it clear it was still a work in progress. Yet it also gave him the sense it was "done."

"Say, is the formation functional after this infusion part?" Jake asked.

"Yes," the snake confirmed. "However, as the Chosen has no doubt noticed, the work is far from done. The Malefic One has plans beyond a simple teleporter requiring your presence. He wishes to allow it to hold more functions that will be helpful to the Chosen later on."

Jake nodded, not asking any further. One thing was clear—the current formation was already far more potent than what Chris had managed to make. Then again, this had been created by a C-grade with innate talent, while the other one had been made by a low-level D-grade. Thinking about it further, the fact that Chris could even make the monument, to begin with, was impressive. Now, as much as it sucked, the monument site had been turned into a graveyard. A memorial and reminder.

They did not exchange any more words before they reached what Jake assumed to be the center of the formation. At that center was an intricate circle with green, vein-like pulsing fissures leading away from it and into the tunnels. The very epicenter held a pillar of metal Jake did not recognize with even more advanced scripts on it. Jake could feel it was a natural treasure of some kind, but he had no clue as to its properties.

"My Lord, if you would do me the honors of stepping into the center circle and blessing the pillar with the Touch of the Malefic Viper?" the snake said to Jake.

Jake did as asked, using One Step to enter the center circle and activate Touch of the Malefic Viper as he touched the pillar. The moment he did so, he felt a response from the pillar, and the energy Jake injected was guided through magical channels in the metal. Jake gladly complied and infused his energy into these channels, and the metal began to glow dark green.

The fissures of green energy began to shine brighter all throughout the spacious cavern, and Jake felt part of his own presence being mimicked by the pillar. He felt a pull on the part of himself that made him a Chosen—the natural treasure taking everything in. A few minutes passed as Jake simply infused his energy, the treasure naturally guiding him to do so until it stopped wanting anything.

At that moment, Jake felt an odd connection form, and the pillar cracked as parts of it fell off. The shards that fell floated in mid-air, then reassembled into a roughly ten-centimeter-long shard of metal filled with runic lines and humming with energy.

Jake reached out and grabbed it, making him instantly know what it was. It was there to control this entire magic circle.

"It is done!" the snake said with much happiness. "Truly marvelous! I thank the Chosen for blessing us with his presence and displaying his prowess. From my understanding, the shard you just received shall function as the control catalyst for the formation, allowing you to teleport to a corresponding circle outside of this universe."

"I see. Excellent work," Jake said, having already felt it himself.

As he stood there in the center circle, he knew he could activate it and be teleported to the First Universe if he so wished. He even felt like he didn’t necessarily need to be in the center circle, but that he could quite easily draw up a smaller circle that allowed him to tap into the concepts of this main formation to teleport from elsewhere.

Jake marveled at the shard a bit longer and analyzed the formation as best he could, but he did not have long before something else caught his attention. An aura approached through the tunnel—one far faster than the old brown snake had been. Far stronger, too. He smiled, as the presence was a very familiar one, and soon enough, an albino figure appeared before him… though she did look quite a bit different.

He failed to hold back a light smile as he briefly bowed his head in gratitude. "It’s been a while. I am sorry for not stopping by earlier and thanking you for keeping Miranda and the others safe."

Miranda’s description of the human form truly didn’t do it justice. She looked human, yes, but also clearly not. The scales were strategically placed throughout her body, not a single one of them of a cosmetic nature. Her reptilian pupils were honed and improved compared to even her snake form, and the skin-like dress she wore was far from just a useless garment, but no doubt had quite the defensive properties. Was the form made to be aesthetically pleasing to humans? Yes, but it was also made with function in mind. Some sacrifices had been made to help her look more human, but overall, the form was refined and incredibly well done. However, her human form did have one major drawback compared to her snake form.

Her demeanor as a shy teenage girl was even more obvious.

The Alabaster Crimsoneye Snake—a mid-tier C-grade—stood nervously and twisted some of her hair around a finger, looking like she didn’t quite know what to say.

"I… eh… I just did as the Chosen would expect of me, you know…" she mumbled.

"You did me a favor, whether you thought it was expected of you or not,” Jake said, still smiling in what he hoped was a welcoming and comforting way. “For that, I am naturally grateful and owe you one. I heard you even spent quite some time with Miranda and the others. I hope they were pleasant guests?"

"Yes, of course!" the snake girl insisted. "Ms. Wells was very nice and taught me a lot. She even helped me with making this settlement and stuff, and I wanted to go visit Haven, but I can’t teleport due to the stupid system.” Even if the last part was grumbled, she looked a bit more comfortable now.

"It is what it is." Jake shrugged. "How about we get out of here and get up to the main office? I think we are done here, right?"

The last part was addressed to the large, brown snake, who nodded. "Yes, my Lord, you have more than done your part. I shall no longer delay you from attending to your matters."

"How come Old Grumpy isn’t using his human form?" the snake girl asked with a questioning look. “He has been working on it so hard.”

Jake scratched his chin. "We decided telepathy was more efficient."

A bald-faced lie that the albino snake nodded to instantly… before suddenly looking faintly horrified. "Would… Would the Chosen prefer for me to use telepathy, too?"

"Hm?" Jake said, surprised. "No, I prefer your human form and talking like this."

Again, a bit of a lie. Jake didn’t really care much either way if the snake was in human or beast form or used telepathy or not when they spoke. But he had enough awareness to know that the snake girl had only become a snake girl to try and better cater to what Jake wanted, and he saw no reason not to make her happy by saying he preferred her human form. When being kind was free and not a hassle, why not?

She smiled and nodded. "Yes, my Lord! Shall we head upwards, then?"

"Let us," Jake said as he began walking through the tunnel, followed by the snake girl. That was when he remembered one of the most important things he had to ask. "By the way, did you ever settle on a name you wanted?"

She stopped for a millisecond when he asked, getting all shy again. "I… I had a really hard time deciding. Ah! Not because the suggestions of the Chosen were bad, but solely due to my own lack of naming sense! I loved both Scarlett and Allie, and I even suggested combining them as Scallie…"

That would have been a perfectly fine name, Jake approved internally.

"…but Ms. Wells shot that down. But… I still loved both, so I thought of maybe still combing them somehow? That is when Ms. Wells said that humans can actually have more than one name, or even have a first and a last name. So… I thought maybe go with Scarlett Allie? Or Allie Scarlett? Or make it the last name, so maybe Scarlett Allieson?"

Jake considered it and nodded. "I think all of those are fine, but does Allieson fit? Normally the ‘son’ part comes from a parent or ancestor or some other family member called that."

"My mom or dad could have been called Allie?" the snake girl said without a hint of joking in her voice.

"You know what? Who is to say?" Jake smiled and shook his head. Should I begin to call Sylphie “Sylphie Hawkson” now? Wait, how does it even work when she is a daughter… Who the hell even made up this entire stupid naming convention? And people call my naming sense bad; that is no more original than adding "ie" at the end of someone’s race name.

"Then… Then can I be Scarlett Allieson from now on?" she asked in a shy tone.

"Sure, if that is what you want," Jake said, nodding.

"Then I want that name," she said with affirmation.

Jake stopped and turned around to extend a hand. "Well, then, nice to meet you, Scarlett Allieson. You can just call me Jake Thayne."

Scarlett looked even shyer as she extended her small hand and took his. "Ah… the pleasure is mine?"

Miranda has done some socialization work on this one, Jake joked internally as he turned around and continued walking towards the main building above.

The two of them only exchanged some casual chatter as they made their way toward the surface for a proper meeting… though he did fail in getting her to call him Jake or even Mr. Thayne or something a little less formal than "Chosen."

But hey, baby steps. One had to be patient with teenagers, after all.

Chapter 65

C-grade Checklist

Scarlett had a hard time imagining it. The first time she met the Chosen had been so brief, and she had barely had any time to talk to him since he was busy making his way through the mangrove forest. She also hadn’t fully realized who he was back then. With time, she’d come to understand and begun to think about how she could make herself useful to the Forefather and his Chosen.

She’d naturally been elated when the Chosen trusted her enough to defend his comrades from danger, and even more happy when those comrades chose to stay. Ms. Wells had even taught Scarlett so many things. The more senior servant of the Forefather’s Chosen had told her about how some enemy Chosen of an extremely powerful god had backstabbed the Forefather’s Chosen and tried to kill him. Or, well, maybe the goal was not to kill him? Scarlett wasn’t sure. All she knew was that several comrades of the bad Chosen had been killed and the coward had fled, resulting in the Malefic’s Chosen taking over the world just as one would expect. As things should be.

Now, after his victory, he had finally returned to the Mangrove, where they were doing everything to help him—Old Grumpy snake was even making a formation for the Chosen to teleport to the Order as he pleased.

But what she had truly had a hard time imagining was not any of his feats, but his demeanor and sheer presence. Scarlett had met many humans and beasts, but one thing was for sure:

The Chosen was the coolest of them all.

Like, he was so cool in everything. He was only D-grade, sure, but Scarlett felt like she walked beside a far more powerful beast than herself. Logically, she knew she didn’t, but his presence was still awe-inspiring. To add on, he had not a shred of fear. Scarlett had honed her skills in evaluating humans. She could quite literally smell fear and weakness, and any kind of nervousness would be clear before her eyes. Yet she felt none of those things from the Chosen. In fact, she was the one who felt scared and nervous when she walked with him… How couldn’t she? He was the Chosen of the Forefather.

"Scarlett," the Chosen said, making her feel all bubbly inside from him using her name, "have you considered what your future plans are?"

Scarlett was perplexed for a moment about what he meant. Thinking a bit about it, she didn’t really have any plans besides helping the Chosen. The formation was not anything she could help with, and the Mangrove was firmly under their control. Even if she was not there alone, the other C-grades could easily handle anything that cropped up. Besides that, her only plan had been to maybe explore the ocean and hunt there—something she had already been doing for a while. It wasn’t the best hunting ground, and it often took a long time to find worthy prey, but she had to take what she could get. Worst of all, she had to do the hunting in her true form.

Not that anything she currently did mattered if the Chosen had other thoughts in mind.

"Does the Chosen have anything he wants me to do?" she asked, feeling a bit of hope. Maybe he had more he wanted her to help with?

"No, not anything like that," he answered, making Scarlett a bit disappointed. "I was just wondering if you have considered going to the Order of the Malefic Viper? I have explored a bit of Earth, and while it is possible, I doubt the planet is that good of a place for someone like you to grow. I am positive there are no B-grades, and even peak C-grades would be astronomically rare, assuming they even exist. Meanwhile, going to the Order would open up a multiverse of possibilities.”

Scarlett listened intensely, barely holding herself back from screaming "YES!" after the very first sentence so as to remain respectful. "Going to the Order of the Forefather would be both an honor and a privilege," she answered as courteously as she could with a big smile on her face, even bowing the same way she had seen some young human women do it.

"Great," the Chosen said with a smile. "Now, if possible, can you show me a safe place for a measuring device within the settlement?"

"Naturally," Scarlett complied without asking further questions.

"And can you then do me one other small favor?" the Chosen asked as he turned and looked at her.

"The Chosen does not even need to ask," Scarlett said with conviction.

"Nice—I just wanted you to bite me a few times."

Scarlett froze and took a moment to process what he had asked before her face turned red, and she completely zoned out… only to still hear the very next sentence.

"Eh, to make it fair, I could bite you too?"

In retrospect, maybe Jake’s words could be misinterpreted, but he really couldn’t hold himself back forever when standing next to a snake girl like her. It was irresistible and impossible not to ask for at least a little bite to get some of that sweet snake venom.

From a distance, her venom was not detectable, but when walking right next to her, his Sense of the Malefic Viper kept making him aware that the small snake girl harbored venom capable of killing hundreds of D-grades with a single drop. It was so strong that not even Jake was sure how he could handle it with Palate at legendary rarity, but he just had to give it a go.

It took him a minute to calm the poor snake girl down after she looked to have short-circuited. Once he got her to relax and listen to his explanation, it suddenly made a lot more sense to the girl, though that still added the complexity of her now being super embarrassed she had misunderstood.

"Are you certain, Chosen? My venom is quite potent, and I have only honed it further since I received the Blessing from the Malefic One, my Toxicity stat growing significantly.”

Jake bit into the last part. "You have a dedicated Toxicity stat?" he asked with a raised eyebrow.

"Yes?" Scarlett answered. "Oh! Yeah, humans have different stats. I got a stat called Toxicity that is related to how toxic anything I do is, making it stronger."

"Did it replace any of the nine we humans have?" Jake continued asking curiously.

"I do not have the Intelligence stat. This one allows my toxins to be far stronger, but it does limit my magical capabilities in many other areas.”

"Makes sense," Jake said, nodding. "But I still want some venom for my own Palate skill. It has been a while since I encountered a toxin it proved ineffective against. Don’t worry; if it goes wrong, I have plenty of anti-toxins."

Not that he was sure those would work, but why worry her? Jake was confident in his survival.

"Okay… but…" Scarlett kind of agreed, clearly unsure.

"Aight, you win. No rush—we can always do it after going to the Order, if you want, where we’d have assistance nearby if we do mess it up." Jake then smiled to comfort her. It maybe was also smart to have Meira nearby, as she was a healer. Oh, and Duskleaf.

"Let us wait…" Scarlett said with relief.

"Got it. Now let’s go get this weird machine placed for Arnold."

It only took him a bit before Scarlett showed him a place where he could deposit it safely, and Scarlett even told a C-grade snake to keep an eye on it. Jake activated it right away, watching it spin to life as what looked like a satellite dish emerged from its top. He faintly detected the device sucking in mana.

With that done, Jake didn’t really have any more plans before it was time to go to the World Congress. A Congress that should, for all intents and purposes, be nothing more than a formality.

Scarlett was clearly intent on shadowing him, and he saw no reason not to allow it. It was a bit awkward, though, like going to a birthday party as the oldest cousin and having teenagers ten years younger than yourself follow you around.

Luckily, what he planned next did not include a lot of moving around. With some time to spare, Jake found a nice place to relax and jot down his aptly named pre-C-grade checklist:

1. Become World Leader at the World Congress.

2. Upgrade Sense of the Malefic Viper.

3. Upgrade Sagacity of the Malefic Viper.

4. Go to Order and defeat baby Snappy.

5. Mythical skill creation with the help of sim-Jake.

6. Actually evolve.

Jake nodded at the mental checklist and didn’t immediately notice anything missing. The first item was easy and would come in a couple of days, if all went to plan. As for two and three, upgrading the two skills was something Jake had subtly been working on for a while and had thought a lot about, even during his holiday, and it honestly should not be too hard. Plus, he would use Path of the Heretic-Chosen for both, as he had two uses left.

Four and five, Jake would combine, though it was more accurate to say that Jake wanted to do four during five. Jake knew that he needed a good battle for an upgrade, and he had discussed the skill sim-Jake wanted a lot with his other self. He also knew that it was not as easy as both of them had hoped, and that they would likely need more preparation than first expected. However, in any case, they both knew that live battle was the best time to consolidate everything and make the skill. It was only in a life-and-death situation that Jake’s instincts were at their sharpest, allowing for the best results.

Number six should also be kind of easy. As for the evolution quests, Jake wasn’t worried. In fact, he had a strong feeling as to what they would be. Especially the one for his profession. But rather than theorize, it was better to just see the quest, and the easiest way to do that was to get one more level in his profession.

So why not kill two birds with one stone and also get in a skill upgrade? As for the skill he would upgrade first, it really was a no-brainer. It was the skill Jake should have arguably upgraded as one of the first but had somehow ended up never really focusing on. It was naturally Sense of the Malefic Viper.

Checking the description, Jake focused on the part that mattered:

…Gives a passive ability to detect herbs and poisons in different forms and a strong feeling of their properties and affinities. Allows the alchemist to far more easily detect affinities in the environment and detect areas optimal for cultivating herbs. Massively improves your ability to sense the poison you have inflicted and its effects on any afflicted entities…

Rather than focusing on what the skill currently did, he focused on what it didn’t do. The usual goal when upgrading was to find aspects the Viper’s version had and add those or improve current functions. Feeling herbs and poisons, the skill already did damn well, and the ability to detect affinities was also something Jake found hard to improve upon. Same for detecting poison he had inflicted. Which made him fast conclude he had to focus on adding additional functionality.

An obvious one was the ability to also sense natural treasures, but Jake kind of already could. Most natural treasures gave off intense affinities, so he could find them when close, and if they were of herbal or toxic nature, the skill still worked on them. So, while that would likely be an easy addition, Jake wasn’t sure if that alone would be enough to qualify for an upgrade or even be useful to him. No, he needed something else.

Jake considered what would be useful to him. What he could really need. He had thought about this a lot and even looked at some of the other Malefic Viper skills for inspiration. That did give him some ideas, but ultimately, the direction Jake went in fit him far more. He went as simple as he could.

Perception was by far Jake’s highest stat, and he made use of it in everything he did.

When shaping magic, Jake felt the flow of mana; he felt how it formed and assembled itself, including noticing any mistakes. Jake made many micro-corrections when doing magic, or really anything requiring control.

He also used Perception in combat, even in ways he did not quite understand but that sim-Jake had helped him at least be aware of. He sensed the flow of battle, the concepts of momentum, and many other things that fed his instincts during battle.

Even when it came to stamina, Jake used it. He felt it flow through his body, and he directed it. Because it all came down to one basic concept.

Seeing is understanding, and before something can be controlled, you need to understand or at least be aware of it first. Perception was the first step of everything and, needless to say, had also become a massive aspect of Jake’s methodology in alchemy.

Jake could notice far more than other alchemists when crafting due to his insane Bloodline-boosted Perception. He could learn and understand more simply based on what he could perceive. His collected data from any experiment was immense compared to the average alchemist—something his trip to Skyggen and teaching their alchemists had made extremely clear. But they could still detect a lot during crafting—not due to a Sphere of Perception and an insanely high stat, but due to their skills. Which was why Jake asked a very fundamental question.

Why did Sense of the Malefic Viper not help with anything during crafting? When he first got the skill, he had thought that was maybe just not what Sense of the Malefic Viper was about, but that the skill only revolved around one thing: finding materials. However, it now also helped him with locating places good at growing materials and detecting affinities in general. It even had the function of sensing the poison he had inflicted. So why not allow him to better sense what he was crafting?

The problem was just how to upgrade that. How to try to feel more when crafting using Sense. It didn’t make much sense—pun intended—for Jake to try and do that. He was already trying to feel as much as he could during crafting, and Sense of the Malefic Viper naturally already helped during that, though indirectly.

No, what Jake wanted was not to just feel more, but to feel different. Pick up things he hadn’t before, either because he wasn’t aware of them existing or his Perception somehow hadn’t been high enough.

If Jake was being honest, he would be fine if all the upgrade did was just add a line about increasing the effectiveness of Perception during crafting, as that would be a huge boon in itself, but he knew he needed more.

As he sat in meditation with a snake girl who also chose to "meditate" nearby while throwing looks his way every five seconds, Jake kept tossing around ideas in his mind. While considering all the different options he could possibly see working, he tried to check the Path of the Heretic-Chosen skill, and wouldn’t you know it? He had passed the invisible threshold.

Do you wish to experience the Legacy of the Malefic Viper? Uses remaining: 2

Well, don’t mind if I do, Jake thought, promptly agreeing as his vision turned black.

If he couldn’t figure it out himself, why not see what the Viper had come up with?

Chapter 66

Sensing the Missing Link in Monster Alchemy

When the vision quickly materialized, Jake found himself in a large cave. Extremely dense mana dominated the area, with the source being a humanoid figure sitting in the center. It was naturally the Malefic Viper, who looked to be doing alchemy. The black cauldron in front of him was giving off a faint mist, and the would-be Primordial appeared to be focusing deeply.

Yet after a dozen seconds, Jake noticed the mist change color, and he instantly knew… the creation was ruined.

"Pathetic!" the Viper snapped, cursing as he slapped the cauldron away. The rancid failed brew spilled all over the cavern. "Absolutely pathetic."

His anger was palpable, though the only one he was angry at was himself. Thinking back, Jake had never seen the Viper actually do alchemy normally, making him more than interested in seeing his methodology. With it being part of a vision, the insight Jake got would also be far more substantial.

After a few moments, the Viper sighed and, with a wave of his hand, had the cauldron float over again. A bit of cleaning later, he tried once more. Jake felt the entire process from the beginning this time around. As he did this, he also got a far better feel for the Viper’s level.

Barely C-grade.

Jake did not know if it was a pattern, but he felt like the visions got closer and closer to Jake’s own level with every passing one. While it could be argued that seeing a vision from Villy’s later years would be more beneficial, as he would experience higher-level concepts and more advanced skills, the opposite was also true. Seeing lower-leveled skills made it easier for Jake to pick up insights and comprehend what the Viper did.

In this case, Jake could actually understand what the Viper did quite easily. Primarily due to how pathetically simple his work was… because what the Viper was trying to make wasn’t anything complicated, but just a normal health potion. So, yeah, Villy talking about how his failure was pathetic was kind of on-point.

He also noticed how the cauldron wasn’t anything special. Jake could not Identify it but guessed that it was common or uncommon rarity at most. Seeing these things, Jake became more and more confident about when exactly in the timeline this had happened.

This was just after the Viper had learned to take human form and begun wanting to learn more regular alchemy. As a snake or even winged snake, the Viper had not done alchemy the conventional way, as far as Jake had gathered. Rather than crafting using mana, it was more like using internal energy to hone and store toxins. In humanoid form, the Viper had to switch it up and learn to do alchemy the same way humans did, which was an entirely different approach. An approach he clearly struggled with.

The Viper kept cursing as he failed another crafting attempt, time now being sped up in Jake’s vision. Having experienced these visions so many times before, Jake knew what he was waiting for: the moment of the Viper’s epiphany. Jake didn’t believe the skill would show him the Viper just failing over and over again… though that would be quite funny.

A few more failures happened, all with sped-up time. The level of frustration of the Viper grew with every second, and he even began to take out different booklets to skim through. Basic crafting books about potions.

Jake’s sense of schadenfreude from the Viper sucking so much at potions eventually turned to confusion. Even if the Viper failed a few times, it didn’t make sense for him to keep failing. He was C-grade, and Jake could see Villy’s level of mana control was far beyond the required level to craft a simple healing potion.

Clearly, Villy also realized this problem as he scanned the books one by one. Sometimes he took out the cauldron and tried again, but the process just kept failing. Jake watched on, his frown deepening when he noticed something. There were small flaws… small oversights… in the Viper’s base brew that Jake had never encountered before when he made potions. As time passed, the Viper also noticed this issue and became as stumped as Jake was.

However, another disparity became clear between Jake and the Viper—a disparity Jake had never imagined. He failed to hold back a smile at the realization.

He had more Perception than the Malefic Viper.

Not the real one, obviously, but more than this newly evolved C-grade version of Villy. Villy also didn’t have Jake’s Bloodline or his basic crafting skills, much less a proper cauldron, making it even harder for him to discover whatever stumped him. He truly was like those alchemists at the Court.

As for what Villy lacked, Jake also discovered it quite easily.

All alchemists—those with the profession, that is—possessed crafting skills. Brew Potion was the applicable skill in this instance. However, as a beast, Villy did not have such a crafting skill, and was thus trying to one hundred percent freeform magic the alchemy.

The reason the method failed was because the books expected the Viper to have the required skills. Those skills helped one with so many different things, including automation of certain minor aspects that the Viper was now missing.

With the lacking Perception, it also looked like Villy wouldn’t be able to figure it out. The fast-forwarding of the vision soon stopped having as many pauses as Jake felt time pass. Days turned to weeks, and weeks turned to months. The Viper kept trying to craft basic potions, sometimes getting closer but always failing.

Occasionally he would make a poison, almost as if he was testing whether he still had his touch. Whenever he made poison, he added a bit of his own blood or venom, and he even tried this with potions, naturally failing. Jake had tried that one, and it wasn’t that easy.

After the eighth month of fast-forwarding, the Viper stopped. Villy simply sat there and stared at the cauldron for the longest time, sometimes glancing at the massive pit he had made of failed potions. He looked lost, but not like he had given up.

"What is wrong?" Villy asked himself. "It should work, but it doesn’t. Are monsters just not meant to do alchemy? No… I can do it; I am just missing something."

The Viper stood up and went over to the pit of health potions he had failed to make. He knelt down and scooped up some of it to drink, sneering at the horrible taste. Jake himself also faintly tasted it in his mouth, though he wasn’t sure if it was due to shared senses or just remembering the time he’d tried to taste that rancid crap himself.

"Nothing," the Viper said to himself after a few moments, Jake knowing he had used Palate.

Falling onto his back, the Viper stared at the cave’s ceiling. After a few moments, he sat up and, to Jake’s surprise, spat some liquid into the palm of his hand. Jake saw the liquid and felt its toxic properties. Yet he also felt the Vitality-based properties and similarity to the failed health potions. The Viper had consumed some of it and refined it into a potent toxin using his own body.

The Viper shook his head again as he tossed the liquid away. A few more moments passed until, slowly, a frown formed on his brows. The frown soon changed into a look of realization as his eyes shot open.

"Maybe…" the Viper muttered as he quickly ran over to the cauldron.

Jake was unsure what Villy had realized, and thus he observed intently. His intuition told him what he had been waiting for was about to happen.

Villy picked up the cauldron and sat with both of his hands on it as he usually did, but then did something unexpected. His hands faintly glowed with energy as mana was infused into the cauldron—far more mana than usual. Sharp fingernails dug into the metal, and Jake felt it slowly change. Touch of the Malefic Viper was active, yet he was not transmuting it or even corrupting it, simply… attuning it?

That was when Jake’s point of view changed, and the best part of the vision began. He merged with Villy, and the senses of the Viper fully became his own. On top of his usual ones, of course. The moment the merge happened, Jake felt a connection with the cauldron in front of him, and Jake soon realized what the Viper was doing.

He was forcefully soul-binding the cauldron.

It was something that was honestly a bad idea in nearly all cases, but Jake soon came to understand. Because as he Soulbound it, he also slowly infused a small part of his soul into the cauldron—something he could only do if a proper connection had been formed with his soul first.

With both hands still on the cauldron, he summoned the ingredients: water, flowers, grass. It was all gradually deposited into the cauldron, and it did not take long for Jake to feel a difference. He could detect what was going on inside the cauldron so intimately that it just felt… odd. It was as if the cauldron was actually part of his body, like a second stomach.

A metaphor that Jake came to learn, in the very next moment, was very apt.

Because another skill also responded at that moment. During all crafts, some vapor would be released while the desired energies got extracted, and some minor parts would always go to waste. This just always happened, and there was no way around it. The loss was often negligible, and the lost parts were undesirable, but it was there. There to be consumed.

Palate of the Malefic Viper thrummed to life as the Viper absorbed these unwanted parts of the brew while it was still ongoing. He then did something else unexpected: He directly absorbed parts of the brew through the cauldron walls as though they were the walls of his stomach.

Jake felt his own Soulshape—one that was now merged fully with the Viper’s—and saw that it looked different. The cauldron had become a part of his Soulspace in a fashion similar to a phantasmal limb, and Jake also knew that this technique was insanely risky. Risky… but effective.

For the Viper, it had one especially effective feature. Because Jake, sharing senses with the Viper, instantly felt an aspect of Sense of the Malefic Viper he did not possess. Not because it was a potent application, but because it simply wasn’t one Jake needed: It allowed the Viper to far better sense anything alchemical inside of his body.

In fact, it was probably a pretty normal skill for most beasts to have. Sandy clearly had a skill similar to it so they could absorb natural treasures they ate, and Jake guessed many other monsters did too. How else would they analyze and break down natural treasures they ate if they could not properly sense them?

With the Viper, there was also the aspect of him honing his poison. Scarlett had already mentioned how she effectively cultivated to improve her own venom internally, and Jake also knew the Viper could do something similar. In other words, the best kind of alchemy the Viper was capable of in this vision was essentially a form of internal alchemy—a skill he could now transfer to the outer world through the insane idea of partly merging with a cauldron.

Jake felt how the Viper now finally noticed these small missing pieces and nearly instantly put two and two together. The first attempt at crafting failed, and a booklet appeared in front of his head. Villy looked at it, burning new words into the paper as he added personal notes.

Four crafting attempts later, the Viper had created a new crafting method for healing potions. Jake had been merged with the Viper throughout and focused intensely on how the Viper had managed to fuse with the cauldron.

He felt parts akin to his upgraded Fang there, especially the part where a weapon effectively became an extension of his body. In fact, it was nearly identical. Aspects from Touch of the Malefic Viper were also present. All in all, Jake began to wonder if he’d maybe only gotten this vision now because he’d needed to see the others first…

Not that it mattered now.

Jake understood the concept and was confident. The final part of the vision showed the Viper stopping the use of the skill as he unfused from the cauldron.

This resulted in the cauldron crumbling into ash the very next moment. As it did so, Villy felt a wave of exhaustion that Jake shared, as the soul energy had effectively been discarded. The lost mental energy was also immense, and Jake felt how the Viper’s natural regeneration had faintly slowed due to his strained soul.

This was what Jake meant when he said risky. It was kind of like using a boosting skill during combat, just for alchemy. There would be a backlash, and Jake would experience it too if he used this new application. The thing is… did he really have to go as far as the Viper did? With it being Soulbound, just using some of the concepts Villy applied should yield some results…

Just as he thought that, time rewound, and he started over from when the Viper had his epiphany. Without having to focus on anything else, Jake felt everything. He tried to truly be one with the Viper and experience what Villy experienced.

It only took one more rewind before he fully got it.

[Sense of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – The Malefic Viper’s greed for natural treasures is never-ending. You are following his path for your senses to see all that which you desire. Your desire for knowing the suffering you bring upon your foes has brought you even further down this path. Gives a passive ability to detect herbs and poisons in different forms and a strong feeling of their properties and affinities. Allows the alchemist to far more easily detect affinities in the environment and detect areas optimal for cultivating herbs. Massively improves your ability to sense the poison you have inflicted and its effects on any afflicted entities. Adds an increase to the effectiveness of Sense of the Malefic Viper based on Perception. Passively provides 1 Perception per level in Prodigious Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your gaze scour the multiverse for all that is rightfully yours.

-->

[Sense of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – The Malefic Viper’s greed for natural treasures is never-ending, his desire to discover all the world has to offer ceaseless. Gives a passive ability to detect herbs and poisons in different forms and a strong feeling of their properties and affinities. Allows the alchemist to far more easily detect affinities in the environment and detect areas optimal for cultivating herbs. Massively improves your ability to sense the poison you have inflicted and its effects on any afflicted entities. Allows you to temporarily merge a part of your soul into a Soulbound cauldron or similar crafting device, making it effectively act as part of your body. Even without fully merging your soul, you will still receive all sensory benefits from using a Soulbound cauldron or similar crafting device. Adds an increase to the effectiveness of Sense of the Malefic Viper based on Perception. All effects of Sense of the Malefic Viper are further improved within the body of the alchemist. Passively provides 3 Perception per level in Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your gaze scour the multiverse for all that is rightfully yours; may all truths lay bare before you.

As always, a bit of flavor text had changed, but it mostly remained the same. The changes were as expected, with it now adding the part about merging a part of his soul with a Soulbound cauldron, but he was happy to see that it still retained all sensory benefits even without merging himself with it. Jake innately felt that the only reason to merge with the cauldron was for Palate absorption.

Finally, it also had an increased effect within his body now. Jake didn’t really see this part being that useful to him, but hey, it was there and kind of another argument for merging with a cauldron. Oh, and of course, the expected bonus to Perception from upgrading the skill. Given his level, it was a lot of Perception. 200 Perception, to be exact, and that was before all percentage bonuses, meaning it was, in reality, 350.

Of course, this was only the math because of one more detail…

Jake had finally reached level 199 in his profession—the peak of D-grade.

Chapter 67

A Feathery Reunion

Jake was still within the vision of the Viper repeatedly doing alchemy but no longer focusing much on it. As odd as it was to say, Jake didn’t really have much to learn from the current Viper within this Record Fragment. Jake was already better than him when it came to making potions, and he had already seen all he needed to see during the first few rewinds.

Checking his notifications, Jake saw the level-up.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 199 - Stat points allocated, +10 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (D)] has reached level 197 - Stat points allocated, +15 Free Points*

197, Jake thought. He could almost taste the evolution now. With this level and his reaching the peak of D-grade, he also got one more thing: his very first evolution quest. Jake checked it, and if he was being honest, it was pretty much exactly what he expected.

Profession Evolution Quest

To walk the Path of a Heretic-Chosen is to not simply be given the power of your Patron, but to claim it. With every step, you move closer to the Malefic One, yet you remain a heretic, unswayed by the Records of a Primordial, as they fail to supersede your being. Go forth, claim the Legacy of the Malefic Viper, and make his Records yours to wield.

Objective: Upgrade skills related to the Legacy of the Malefic Viper to legendary rarity (8/6)

Jake had already completed it. It could be called anticlimactic, but as mentioned, Jake had expected this outcome. Why wouldn’t he have?

Evolution quests were not about pushing the person to their limit; they were designed to test that the person had reached the expected achievements of the class or profession. If it required Jake to do something insane for even him, all it would have been proof of was that Jake had not lived up to expectations during his journey to C-grade.

Not that this one was easy… It required Jake to upgrade at least six skills to legendary, and based on the "8/6," it seemed to still count more upgrades he got now. He read that as an indication that the system still recognized him upgrading more as part of the quest. Especially because the quest was still there and had not just been completed automatically.

Jake knew he could evolve his profession there and then if he wanted. Needless to say, he had no interest in this, as he was aiming for the Perfect Evolution and also wanted to upgrade the last skill anyway.

Smiling to himself, Jake closed the quest menu just as he felt the vision was also about to end. He had barely been paying attention and still found himself merged with the Viper, but as had happened before… the vision extended a bit beyond the usual this final time.

Still merged with the Viper, Jake felt the would-be Primordial’s happiness at his success, and he celebrated a bit by himself. Jake just smiled alongside Villy, happy for his buddy’s success, even if it was just a peek into history. Yet, mere moments before the vision ended, he felt something observing him. Observing Villy.

A powerful presence that Villy did not at all notice, but one Jake naturally picked up on. A familiar gaze that Jake had felt during a previous vision.

The First Sage?

The vision ended just as Jake became sure of the source and returned to the real world.

Scarlett felt all giddy as she guided the Chosen around the Mangrove. The thought of getting invited to the sacred Order of the Malefic Viper had never even crossed her mind, but the more she considered it, the more excited she became.

The Chosen was also nice and allowed her to stay with him during his visit to the Mangrove. She knew she had much to learn from him and would observe his every action whenever she could. Scarlett also noticed how the other humans of the Mangrove looked at him, and she felt their emotions. Their odd mix of emotions.

Fear and nervousness were two of the strongest senses other humans got from watching the Chosen. It was only right to feel fear before a superior being, and she could only approve of their understanding to not approach and needlessly annoy or delay the Chosen in his matters.

After he was done with his business, they went to the largest building in the Mangrove, where she led the Chosen to a room for him to meditate in. He did also make some weird comments along the way… like asking for her to bite him…

She didn’t get it. Was physical contact not rather shunned by humans? Also, did he really trust her enough to allow her to use her venom on him? It was all a bit too much for her, and she was happy that he decided to meditate for a while so she could further observe him.

But… not long into meditation, she felt something. An odd shift in the environment as whispers of a presence that did not belong on a small planet like Earth appeared. Her eyes opened wide when she recognized it, and she stared wide-eyed at the Chosen as her heart began pounding from the pressure. Then, at the very next moment, he disappeared, leaving only a lingering presence behind.

Scarlett tried to calm herself down, but she could not stop herself from shaking. That had been the presence of the Malefic One… the Forefather of her entire race. What had the Chosen done? It was like he, for a moment, had become the Forefather himself, their Paths and Records uniting.

Not long passed before he reemerged, the aura still present for a moment before it dispersed like it had never been there, leaving only the Chosen deep in thought…

Jake kept frowning as he sat in the main office in the Mangrove. Why had the First Sage looked at Villy? How had he been aware of him? Villy’s description had said that the first time they met was when the Viper tried to sneak in and learn from the First Sage, but this vision said otherwise. Or maybe it didn’t—at least, not from the perspective of the Viper.

Villy was not omniscient, and Jake began to suspect that his choice of seeking out the First Sage had more to it than the Viper knew. Had he been led into seeking out the man? If so, for what purpose? Did he just want someone to kill him, like Villy had said? Leave a student, perhaps? Something entirely different that Jake had no damn clue about?

All were likely, with the final one being the most likely. Shaking his head, Jake decided not to mull it over too much. He wasn’t even sure if he wanted to ask Villy about it… Maybe it was just better to keep it to himself and hope that a future vision could give some insight. Villy clearly cared a lot about this First Sage, and Jake didn’t want to pollute a memory for no reason. Yeah, best keep it to himself and return to more current matters.

Jake opened his eyes and regarded the snake girl in the room, who was staring at him with wide-open, starry eyes.

"I… I felt the presence of the Forefather,” she said with much interest. “What happened? Did you go see the Malefic One?"

"You can say that." Jake smiled. "I used one of my skills as a Chosen—that is all."

She just nodded enthusiastically. "Thank you for allowing me to witness it! I will never forget this honor."

Jake smirked and shook his head, not having the heart to tell her that he just didn’t really see any reason to hide something like this. She knew he was the Chosen already, so him doing Chosen stuff was just to be expected.

Oh, and finally… Jake kept forgetting about the part that blasted out the presence of himself and the Viper whenever he used the skill. In his defense, he had not actually planned on just using the skill right away, but when he focused on stuff, he kind of tended to forget everything and everyone around him, with it already having led to outing himself to everything from friends in the Order to projections within dungeons.

"Would you mind if I did some alchemy?" Jake then asked the snake girl. It was more a rhetorical question, as she, of course, instantly nodded. "Thank you. I plan on staying here for a bit before heading back to Haven before the World Congress.”

Scarlett naturally didn’t voice even a sliver of negativity.

Jake smiled again at her and decided to get some practice in with his new skill, and he had just the thing to craft: Perception Elixirs. He did have some already in storage, but he wanted to craft some more before he evolved anyway. He had 300 stat points to get and saw no reason not to claim them right away. Could he increase other stats? Sure, but Jake wanted Perception.

He also still had some materials in store, so he could get started right away. The moment Jake summoned the cauldron and laid his hands on it, he instantly felt the difference from the newly upgraded skill. It was like everything within the cauldron appeared clearer than before, even if it was currently empty.

With a mental command, Jake manipulated the very air within it. He felt the different affinities and, out of curiosity, focused on them. Water, wind, space, time, nature, wood…. So many affinities he recognized. Jake chose one and strained himself, and in the middle of the cauldron, a small droplet of water began to condense as Jake extracted the humidity from the air.

Definitely noticeable, Jake concluded as he got to work.

Adding the ingredients, he tried to discern what the difference truly was. In all honesty, the upgrade did not help much during crafting like this, as there really weren’t many details he couldn’t already catch with his Perception. It was far more effective during experimenting—that was for sure. He also faintly considered trying out the soul-merging effect, but he decided against it when his intuition warned him of the outcome.

Villy had destroyed his cauldron, and while Jake was confident the Altmar Cauldron would survive, he was certain it would be damaged and be in need of repair afterward. It had the rune on the bottom to accomplish this, but it would take time, and as mentioned, he didn’t need it.

Thus, Jake just dove into the alchemy as time passed. Scarlett silently stayed by his side for nearly two days, staring at everything he did with interest. She was damn lucky Jake had been conditioned by Villy’s constant staring, allowing him to completely ignore it and make plenty of elixirs.

Once it was about time to head back to Haven, Jake went on a drinking binge.

You have assimilated a strong energy of Perception.

+5 Perception.

You have assimilated a strong energy of Perception.

+5 Perception.

You have…

Elixir after elixir went down, and seeing as he had enough, he even offered some to Scarlett. She graciously accepted but only wanted a single one, which was a bit weird. Especially as she looked to have no interest in drinking the elixir but simply held onto it for a while before storing it away.

Another easy 300 Perception in the bag, Jake thought, smiling after he was done drinking. Over just a few days, Jake had gotten around one thousand more Perception from the skill upgrade, elixirs, and Free Points, making him feel quite good about himself. Jake knew that stat distribution also greatly impacted evolutions, and he wanted to make it absolutely clear to the system that he was a Perception-based guy.

At least, that was what he told himself to excuse his decision.

"Thanks for accommodating me," Jake said to Scarlett as he prepared to head back. "After the World Congress, I will come back here, and we will travel for the Order of the Malefic Viper, so make your preparations, alright?"

"Yes!" Scarlett enthusiastically nodded. "Will you need me to do or bring anything in particular?"

"I won’t need you to bring anything, and while we do need to talk about a few details related to my identity at the Order, that can wait.”

"Very well," she acknowledged. "I once more thank the Chosen for blessing us with his presence."

Jake waved it off. "That is part of what you will need to work on fixing. Be more casual, alright? Anyway, I am off!"

With that, Jake headed for the teleporter, with Scarlett still following him and bidding him goodbye.

A swift teleportation later, Jake found himself back at the Fort. The convenience of these teleporters was truly, well, convenient, even for someone like Jake, who had quite the insane travel speed. Jake still chose to fly back towards Haven—not because it would be in any way faster, but because he had already felt the aura approach, and he decided to meet halfway. As for who this presence was?

It was a small, green ball of feathery death.

They had been apart for a long time. Thinking about it, this was probably their longest separation since the little featherball had been born.

His grin only grew as he flew forward and felt her approach pretty fucking fast. She had gotten a lot swifter—that was for sure—and it did not take long before he saw the small green form enter his vision and barrel straight toward him.

[Sylphian Eyas – lvl 199]

She had reached the peak of D-grade—something entirely expected. Jake stopped in mid-air and opened his arm wide to hug the bird. However, Sylphie had other plans. She expertly dodged his attempt, flying in between his hands and dodging beneath his legs before doing a quick circle, landing perfectly on top of his head.

Sylphie stood proudly, as if she had reclaimed her rightful place, and Jake nearly failed to hold back a laugh as he raised a hand and nuzzled her. "It’s been a while, eh?"

"Ree!" Sylphie screeched in complaint, making Jake indeed fail to hold back his laugh.

"I missed you too."

She showed mercy and allowed Jake to lift her off his head and give her a hug. Sylphie had not changed in the slightest since they separated. Well, besides getting a lot stronger and making Jake’s Sense of the Malefic Viper now pick up how the wind mana itself seemed to change in her vicinity.

"Did you have fun with your adventures?" he asked, still holding the small hawk in his arms like she was a newborn baby.

"Ree! Ree!" she semi-explained as Jake play-fought with her talons.

"Lots of strong beasts, huh?" Jake nodded. "Managed to take down some C-grades?"

Sylphie proudly screeched in affirmation, then went on a tirade of screeches explaining what had happened. Jake nodded along, still unsure how the hell he understood what she meant. She had gone to the cloud layer where C-grades lived and managed to defeat a few C-grades while hunting with Carmen.

Speaking of Carmen… "Where did you leave Carmen? Isn’t she also here?"

"Ree!"

"She isn’t that slow."

"Ree!"

Jake laughed in agreement as the hawk insisted. "Okay, she is a little slow."

Feeling victorious, Sylphie once more brought the topic back to her adventures. Jake listened intently, continuing to nod along while slowly flying back towards Haven, and he at least managed to extract the fact that Carmen was back there talking with the Sword Saint, Miranda, and Arthur.

Oh… and two others who had also come back to Haven for a visit. Two hawks Jake hadn’t seen for even longer than Sylphie: her parents, Hawkie and Mystie.

Chapter 68

The Eve Before the Third World Congress

Hawkie and Mystie had been busy birds, as far as Jake knew. His visits to Haven had just never really intersected with when they visited, and after Sylphie had left with him and Carmen, the two hawks had bothered visiting even less, as they hadn’t really had any reason to go.

Instead, they’d focused on leveling, hunting as a pair in the sky and in the vast forest Haven was on the outskirts of. Jake knew that neither of them was particularly strong for their levels, but they weren’t weak either. He would place them firmly in the mid-to-high-tier level of beast variants, primarily due to Mystie’s unique type of magic and Hawkie’s high striking power. Together, they were especially strong with their developed combo attacks and skills, bringing them firmly into the high-tier category.

Yet, even knowing this, Jake was surprised when he saw them from afar, the two of them waiting on a branch just at the entrance to the forest.

[Stormsong Hawk – lvl 178]

[Mystsong Hawk – lvl 176]

You go, mate! Jake thought when he saw Hawkie had surpassed Mystie in level. It did make sense; Mystie was more of a supportive fighter, with Hawkie being the one going in and dealing most of the damage. But, damn, them having both reached such a high level so fast was impressive to him.

Neither of them was a living cheat like Jake, Sylphie, or most of the other people around him. They were just kind-of-strong beasts. Well, okay, that wasn’t entirely accurate. They were the parents of Sylphie, and in the same way that Jake’s parents benefited from Records by being his parents, so did Hawkie and Mystie benefit from Sylphie. Them being friends with Jake also helped them quite a bit, though Jake reckoned their relationship with Sylphie meant more. Then again, Sylphie benefited a lot by being close to Jake, so he did help quite a bit by proxy?

Anyway, Records were complicated, and even if he helped, it was still their own effort that had brought them to high-tier D-grade.

Jake smiled as he saw them and raised a hand to wave. Sylphie remained cradled in his arms, clearly content with not having to move as Jake flew over to her parents.

Mystie looked down at her daughter somewhat judgingly, while Hawkie flew down towards him. What looked like a fork of lightning appeared and floated in mid-air in front of Jake as Hawkie landed on it at eye height with Jake.

"Good to see you again, mate," Jake greeted the hawk. His first monster friend, if you didn’t count the King.

Hawkie simply nodded and looked at Jake holding Sylphie.

"Does feel a bit bad to be surpassed by your own daughter, huh?" Jake asked.

To his surprise, Hawkie didn’t agree. Quite the opposite. Jake sensed only happiness at how strong Sylphie was, with not a shred of jealousy. This only made Jake smile more. Here’s to healthy family dynamics.

What was the saying…? Jake couldn’t remember, but he remembered the gist of it. Celebrate the success of others and mourn their losses. Feeling jealous or angry because someone you proclaimed to care about experienced success was just a sign of you being an egotistical asshole. It was fine to feel a bit miffed, sure, but that should be trumped by the happiness of seeing someone you care about succeed.

"Or maybe not," Jake corrected as he looked down at Sylphie and nuzzled the feathers on her stomach. Like an angry cat, she fought back with her talons, but Jake just grinned as he adeptly dodged them to tickle her. "She sure has grown, eh?"

"Ree!" Sylphie screeched in agreement, with Hawkie just giving a slight nod. Hawkie was as reserved as ever, and Mystie still seemed a bit cautious around Jake even after all this time. At least she seemed happy to stay at a distance and just observe what happened.

"Should we head back?" Jake asked. "You can tell me what you two have been up to in the meantime. How about you join us, too, Mystie?"

He looked up at the hawk with a smile. She quickly relented—not due to Jake, but the wide eyes of Sylphie staring up at her, making her fly down and join them as they slowly made their way through the forest. He already kind of knew what Hawkie and the others had been doing and what they’d hunted, but it was always good to hear it from the primary source.

The two of them had mainly focused on safe hunts and not biting off more than they could chew. Mystie was damn good at stealth by now, from what he gathered, and allowed them to ambush foes or escape areas with dangerous monsters they could not beat. Jake also came to learn that, apparently, the massive lightning tree in the sky had died several months ago after Hawkie had gone for a round of absorption. That made Jake a touch sad… until he heard Sylphie chip in about how there were many more of those trees up in the higher cloud layers where C-grades lived. Bigger ones, too, making Jake wonder where the hell they came from.

With more than one, he could only assume it was some breed of tree. He had assumed that the massive lightning tree had been the "main tree," with the smaller crystal trees spread around it being its seedlings, but now Jake began to wonder… What if the big one had also just been another seedling itself? Did this mean there was some massive, awesome lightning tree somewhere?

Anywho, the two proud hawk parents had explored far more of the forest than anyone else. Jake had already known that C-grades existed deep in the forest, but they had indeed confirmed their presence and how there were a lot of them. Needless to say, Hawkie and Mystie were not equipped to fight C-grades quite yet, even if they had gotten a lot stronger.

They had an enjoyable talk as they made their way back to Haven, with Mystie even joining in and adding some information with images made of Myst here and there.

Soon enough, they reached Haven, and Jake felt the many presences within. Everyone had gathered, it seemed, and the group now also included Carmen. He did not detect another monster with the King, but he’d kind of assumed he had thought of one. Not that it mattered; they could always find this last council member after Jake was World Leader.

Jake waltzed into the main office, still holding Sylphie. However, she seemed to want to keep her dignity, as she wrestled herself free and flew up to land on top of his head to prove her dominance. Jake cracked a smile as he entered the room, and everyone looked at him.

"I apologize for my late arrival, but I have to announce a change in plans.” Adopting a wide grin, he continued, “Going by hierarchy, it has become clear to me that the true leader of Earth should not be me, but the mighty Sylphie.”

"Sold," Carmen answered with a smirk.

"Wouldn’t it be the same?” Miranda said, shrugging. “Not like you plan on actually doing any work.”

"I have no complaints either," even the Sword Saint chimed in.

The King did not even dignify his announcement with a response, while Arthur looked genuinely confused for a few moments before realizing it was just a bad joke.

"Thanks for the support and confidence, everyone," Jake said, chuckling as he went to take a seat. Hawkie and Mystie had both chosen to stay outside and flown towards the good old lodge. Probably to steal his bananas.

"Let us get to work," Miranda cut in, actually trying to get something done. "Arthur was just telling us how he has spread the word of our arrangement, and despite quite a bit of pushback, things seem to be on track, with most understanding the nuance of the situation and choosing to support us. During the Congress itself, we should be able to convince the rest by actually displaying a united front.”

"As for the Noboru Clan, things have mostly calmed down.” The Sword Saint sighed. "There shall at least be no opposition to voting you World Leader."

"We have claimed more Pylons and expanded, and naturally, all shall vote according to my will," the King said. "When it comes to this final member of the council, I have attempted to seek out this whale you spoke of, but I ran into an obstacle."

"Oh?" Jake asked, surprised. "What’s wrong?"

"You asked me to find a sea creature in a vague direction—one living far away in an area filled with C-grades that you expect me to hopelessly search through with a damaged soul.”

"So what you are saying is that you suck at tracking and stealth. Got it. I guess I will just have to call the divine hotline to try and get this whale guy on board. After the Congress, of course." Jake smiled.

"I congratulate myself for not wasting my time on such a pointless task, then," the King said, scoffing before falling silent.

"I guess it’s my turn?" Carmen spoke up after a brief pause. "Eh, those from Valhal will vote for you—at least Sven, that bastard, told me so. He also told me to apologize to you, so I am sorry that Sven and the moronic moron higher-ups fucked up like the morons they are."

"Apology accepted," Jake said with a nod. "Partly. Valhal is not getting out of this scot-free, but we can talk about what form of compensation I find agreeable. Quite frankly, it wouldn’t matter anymore if they refused to vote for me, would it?"

"No, it would not," Miranda confirmed. "Based on my estimates, you sit on well over eighty percent of the total votes. Remember that many of the nobles who are on the fence are only Lords with one vote, while we have all higher-level nobles on our side."

"See? Even if Valhal decides to be assholes again, we’re good," Jake said to Carmen.

Carmen looked offended for a moment but then took a deep breath. "I had nothing to do with what they did. I didn’t even hear anything about that orange fuck or that bullshit Alliance before everything had already happened."

"I know that," Jake said comfortingly. "But Valhal still needs to pay some kind of recompense. I am sure Sven already predicted this?"

"Probably did," Carmen answered. "I didn’t really listen to much of what he said after he told me to go apologize. Ask him at the Congress. It is his damn fault for asking me to act as a diplomat like this."

"Fair enough." Jake nodded as he turned to Miranda again. "Anything from the Risen at all?"

"No." Miranda shook her head. "But I did confer with my Patrons, and it appears like they have left Earth for good. Which was, according to them, probably better for everyone involved."

Jake frowned. "Why?"

"Well… while the Risen do usually go the diplomatic route, the end result is often still the total domination of any planet they operate on, including eventual terraforming. Chances are they would have left by themselves at some point anyway, or only left a small outpost at most. At least they would have gone for another planet nearby to make their own and not actually remained on Earth."

Her explanation reminded him of the final force he wanted to ask about. "What about the Church? They still have some cities, as far as I recall."

"Kind of?" Miranda said. "It is more just City Lords refusing to accept what happened and still waiting for the Church to call for them. They have fallen one by one in the last month, and only a scarce few remain, all of them in minor settlements of little importance. No, the biggest problem is the refugees from all the major cities, especially Sanctdomo."

Jake once more nodded, knowing there was quite a refugee crisis going on. If the King had not managed to rein in the monsters and their attacks, things would have gotten far worse. The cities the Church used to own were primarily taken by the United Cities Alliance, with the Noboru Clan and even Valhal managing to snatch up a few.

The meeting continued for a bit longer, but there really wasn’t much to discuss ahead of this World Congress. They didn’t even know what kind of votes would happen besides the one for World Leader, so it was impossible to discuss that. All in all, everything was set, and Jake decided to head back to his lodge to chill with the hawks.

Carmen decided to follow him—something he definitely didn’t complain about. It was good to hear about the adventures of her and Sylphie with actual human words. The fact that Mystie, Hawkie, and Sylphie didn’t speak actual words using telepathy or something like that surprised him a bit, but then again, did they have to? The only one Hawkie and Mystie seemed to care about talking to was Jake, and he understood them. And if they didn’t bother learning telepathy, he also doubted they would rush to get human forms.

In fact, it wasn’t that unusual for beasts to never bother getting a human form. A human form had no value for a monster living in the wild and was, in many ways, only a weakness. It also took quite a bit of skill and time to create a usable one, making many lower-tier creatures simply give up and never bother. Then, finally, there was the fact that many beasts saw the human form as inferior, considering it a slight to their honor to adopt one for even a second. Villy had once told a funny story about why all dragons always chose to retain draconic features in their human form without having to: Because they were braggarts who wanted anyone even catching a glimpse of them to still know they were indeed dragons. He didn’t think Mystie and Hawkie were like that, but it was still a toss-up if they’d bother to make one when they reached C-grade.

They also had the advantage of their small forms, allowing them to still travel around places built for human-sized individuals. Big beasts not fitting into human-sized houses were by far one of the primary reasons for human forms being such a widely adopted concept.

Once they entered the valley, Jake was thrown out of his thoughts when he saw the two hawks again, having indeed stolen some of his bananas. They were lucky he was in a good mood and couldn’t scold parents in front of their own kid.

"Hey… are you ready to evolve soon?" Carmen asked him after they had gotten into the lodge and settled down at the table.

Jake finally Identified her and saw that she, at least, was.

[Human – lvl 193]

"Yeah, pretty damn close; I just need some class levels,” Jake answered. “And I got some stuff I want to finish beforehand.”

"Your class?" Carmen asked with surprise. "I only need levels in my profession… Been kind of slow recently. Didn’t really feel like dedicating kills to Valhal or doing any of their bullshit rituals after they lied and tried to screw over my home planet."

"Fair," Jake said, nodding. "But in their defense, I don’t think Valhal actually tried to screw Earth over, and from my understanding, some complicated shit is just going on between a bunch of gods."

"Why would you bother defending them after just talking about wanting compensation?" Carmen asked with a frown.

Jake just smiled. "I am the Chosen of the Malefic Viper. I know stuff. Secret stuff."

"Ass," she shot back.

"I do have one of those, yes," Jake confirmed with a stupid grin.

"Assho—ah, never mind. So, what the hell have you been up to? I don’t know shit compared to everyone else, it feels like.”

"Oh, man…"

Jake once more narrated what had happened, including everything with Sandy and his journey across the planet. Sylphie and the other hawks stayed for a part of it, and then all three of them left to have some quality family time terrorizing the local wildlife, leaving just Carmen and Jake back at the lodge.

"Fucking Ell’Hakan,” Carmen said after Jake was done talking. “Dude is definitely coming back to make trouble, isn’t he?"

"No doubt." Jake nodded. "Though I don’t know if he will mess with Earth again or just aim for me directly. Maybe a mix of both. Either way, I will handle him later. For now, I got too much other stuff to take care of."

"I guess," Carmen said before groaning. "Why does shit have to be complicated? Can’t we just have proper villains who show up and challenge you directly or something like that?"

"That would definitely be preferable," Jake said, smiling. "I much prefer when people can just be direct and cut all the bullshit."

Carmen nodded. “Agree.”

They were both silent for a few seconds before Jake scratched the back of his head. "You know, we got at least a few hours before the World Congress and nothing to do."

Carmen smiled. "I thought you just said you preferred when people were direct?"

"Other people," Jake clarified.

"Goddamn hypocrite," Carmen said, laughing before dragging him outside the lodge for a sparring session.

Followed by dragging him back inside for another kind of sparring session.

Chapter 69

The Third World Congress

Jake and Carmen both lay on the grass in the valley outside of the lodge, staring up at the sky and relaxing after their strenuous wrestling session.

"Why couldn’t we have used the bed, again?" Carmen asked after turning to him.

"That is a meditation bed," Jake said stoically. "Also, it is super old and comes from a dungeon, and I didn’t wanna risk breaking it. Sentimental value and all that."

"As long as you don’t feel the same about the table," Carmen said, referring to the broken pieces of wood in the lodge, as she sat up. "Should we get going? Also… aren’t the others going to start asking questions?"

Jake looked to the side and saw a part of the valley pretty damn banged up from their earlier spar, including quite a few craters. "Nah, I think they will just assume we only sparred. Does it matter either way?"

Carmen thought for a moment. "I guess not, but I would prefer for no stupid rumors to spread."

"Oh, I already got those rumors related to Miranda and me." Jake shrugged.

"Really?" Carmen asked, a bit surprised. "So have you—"

"Nah. Professional boundaries and all. Don’t wanna make things awkward with someone who effectively works for me." Jake shrugged.

"Don’t wanna shit where you eat, huh?" Carmen nodded. "Though, as a Chosen, isn’t everyone below you in the hierarchy? And does your Patron give a fuck about professional boundaries?"

A vivid image of Villy with three witches flashed in his mind as he shook his head. "Oh, the Viper sure doesn’t, but that doesn’t mean I don’t. As for everyone being above me as Chosen, well, if I don’t think someone is below me and they don’t think I am above them, then who the fuck is to decide?"

"Truly masterfully argued." Carmen smirked. "Now, let’s go to that office and get this entire World Congress bullshit done with."

"Fine," Jake agreed, stretching as he walked towards the main office. The others were already waiting there, and not long after, it was time. The invitations were sent out, and once Jake agreed, his vision went black… and he entered the Third World Congress.

The World Congress chamber hit Jake like a bag of bricks filled with nostalgia when he entered. His sphere spread out, and he could only sigh internally. Figures appeared all around him, but some people who had been at every other Congress were notably missing.

Sanctdomo and that Risen city Jake didn’t remember the name of were both gone from the top ten. Jacob and Casper were nowhere to be seen, really hammering home that they were both gone from Earth for good.

Another notable figure that was nowhere to be seen was Eron. Jake had kind of hoped to see him there, but his absence also confirmed for good that he had left Earth, likely with no desire to return. His reason for leaving was still a mystery, and Jake wondered if he knew about Ell’Hakan coming or if it was totally unrelated. Either way, he was gone.

He did at least see some familiar figures he hadn’t heard much about in the last month. Two people in particular. The first one was Maria, the fire archer who had been with Bertram and his party as a mercenary and had helped in the fight with the Monarch of Blood. She looked to be with an entirely different crew, and from what Jake could observe, she had probably split entirely from the Church.

The second person was someone Jake himself had told to be there but was still surprised to actually see. William stood on a platform way at the back of the room and looked unassuming as hell. His presence was oddly muted, and even if he had just appeared, Jake saw his eyes wide open as he looked deep in thought. He didn’t get the feeling William would make any trouble, as he had far too many internal issues to deal with. At least he hadn’t found his Path yet, judging by his level still being 199. In fact, scanning the room, no one at C-grade was present. A few were at level 199 here and there, but no one had evolved. What stumped them, he didn’t know, but he guessed it was either natural barriers caused by Records or an issue with quests.

Standing there and scanning everything, it felt oddly hollow. So little mystery remained about who those unknown City Leaders were. All intrigue about hidden experts on the planet had been killed. Besides a few odd rumors about standout individuals who didn’t bother with politics, there really was nothing. His only hope was in the unexplored parts of the planet and what monsters might hide there.

Jake had appeared on the platform together with the usual suspects. He, Miranda, Lillian, and Neil attended from Haven just like all the other times, but all the others who had been in Haven appeared on their respective platforms. From what Jake could gather, the Sword Saint had given up control of his Pylon when he pretended to die to better sell the ruse, but had now gone and reclaimed it without any opposition. Carmen and Arthur had also appeared at their original Pylon locations despite being in Haven.

He was still looking around when the welcome message appeared.

Welcome to the Third World Congress of Earth.

Two World Congresses have passed, and it is time for the final scheduled one.

The World Congress is an opportunity for the newly integrated denizens of Earth to establish political connections and an arena for discussion, voting, and international politics that can impact the planet as a whole. Note that no fighting will be allowed during the World Congress. Each booth has an aura that will offer privacy to each city.

During the Third World Congress, two votes will be held with a maximum length of five (5) hours per vote. After one vote finishes, the other will immediately begin. During this World Congress, a World Leader must be elected, and if none has managed to accumulate 60% of the total votes, the candidates shall be cut down and options limited until the World Leader is elected.

The first vote will pertain to the election of a World Leader. The World Leader will automatically have their noble rank advance one stage and must be elected during this World Congress. The Second Vote pertains to the final trial of the enlightened races on Earth.

The first vote will automatically begin in thirty (30) minutes.

Jake read it over and saw only minor changes from the last time. More freedom with voting periods, an inclusion that the World Leader must be elected, and finally, information about the vote for a final trial of some kind?

Everyone read it, and Jake also double-checked that the voting rules had not changed since last year.

Voting rules of the World Congress:

The number of available votes is based on the nobility rank of the attending members. The number of votes per nobility rank is as follows:

King: 1000

Prince: 250

Duke: 100

Marquiss: 25

Earl: 10

Viscount: 5

Baron: 3

Lord: 1

The noble in question may distribute their votes as they choose if there are multiple options. The noble may abstain from voting. Votes are final and cannot be appealed. Any agreements will come into effect until the next World Congress or if all included parties choose to revoke it. All tie-breakers will be decided by the highest-ranking noble present at the World Congress.

It was the exact same as last year, indeed. Jake still questioned how and why Prince was a thing, considering the prince was usually the son of the king, but hey, who was he to question the omnipotent system?

Jake also knew that he would advance to Marquiss after this vote. It was still a bit odd that he, as the World Leader, would still be three entire nobility ranks below the Fallen King, but there wasn’t really anything he could do about it. Unique Lifeforms were pretty bullshit like that.

Also, no, the King could not give others nobility ranks. The nobility title of the King was a bit of a weird case in more than one way. Monsters could not have nobility ranks, but despite that, the King had one, which also did make it kind of funny when the system talked to everyone within the Congress like they were among the enlightened races.

After Jake had read through everything, including the usual prompt to vote for World Leader, he turned his attention back to all those in the chamber. He felt many gazes upon him and knew what he had to do. Miranda had told him many times, and sometimes he still had to do a bit of politics. With a mental command, Jake made his mask invisible and clapped his hands together to get everyone’s attention.

"So here we are again at the third World Congress, but we all know this one is quite a bit different than the first two," Jake spoke, the speech only semi-practiced. He was mostly just winging it. Seemed more genuine that way. “With how things have gone in recent times, how couldn’t it be?

"Enemies were invited onto our planet due to naivety, ignorance, stupidity, and deceit. Millions died due to the decisions of a few, and countless more now find themselves struggling from the aftermath. As I am sure you can all see, the Risen are gone. I know many of you didn’t like them, but out of everyone, they were one of the most peaceful factions. At the same time, the Holy Church has also chosen to leave. Why, you might ask? Because they realized their goal of world domination was not feasible, and they were the kind of people who either want everything or nothing." Jake saw a few frowns here and there. Probably the idiots who still believed in the Church.

"Another question you might have is who this invader was. I am aware most of you have no idea, so let me clarify. His name is Ell’Hakan, an alien who has already dominated his home planet and is the Chosen of Yip of Yore, an incredibly powerful god that even the Pantheon of the Holy Church is wary of. His reason for coming here quite honestly had nothing to do with any of you. He never cared about Earth. He came for me."

A bit of chatter was heard here and there, but Jake raised a hand. "I know, I know. Rumor has no doubt gone around that I am the Chosen of the Malefic Viper, an even more feared god than Yip of Yore and one with quite the… let’s just say, reputation. I do realize it is somewhat my own fault for not really bothering to let you all know more about me, leading you to believe I am some evil bastard, but I hope that you have come to realize I have no desire to lead Earth down a bad Path. I just want the planet to survive and be defended, nothing more. That is also what most of you want—for Earth to remain independent—but you must also realize that simply isn’t possible. Without backing, we are like a poor country with pointy sticks trying to defend ourselves from global superpowers. And not just any small, impoverished country, but one with a shitload of oil that everyone wants."

Even more chatter, only a handful of people with some muted chuckling. All of them were people Jake knew, sadly. The joke did not land.

"What I am saying is that Earth would be fucked without someone big and scary to intimidate multiversal forces. Arthur, the former leader of the newly dissolved United Cities Alliance, tried to have Valhal be this big, scary force, but needless to say, his plans fell apart and were built on a foundation of lies and naivety. However, through talks with Arthur, I came to realize that we do want the same thing, so I am proposing that we use my backing as the deterrent. That we use my identity as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper as a shield. Again, I know a lot of you are probably skeptical of this idea, but the Order will have no influence on the planet.”

There were still a lot of skeptics in the hall, but Jake continued nevertheless.

"Instead, Earth will be led by a council of five, me not included. I have no interest in actually leading anything. Thus, everything will be up to their discretion, with me only getting involved in matters I care about or find important. The same way as I have led Haven thus far. And before anyone asks, let me just address the question of why I then don’t just make someone else the World Leader and sit on the council. The easy answer to that one? Because I don’t want to. Because if there is one thing I want less than to become World Leader, it is for someone else to become World Leader." Jake grinned. "Anyway, that was my big speech. I will now take questions."

"How will you—"

"What are—"

"If you—"

People instantly began yelling, and Jake raised a hand to silence them again. "That was a damn joke; I am not actually answering any questions. If you want to know more, ask the people on the council. After the vote."

Someone with a particularly loud voice yelled, "Are we not even gonna dignify a discussion of alternatives? Not even going to act like this is the democratic election it is?"

Jake did not recognize them at all and just shrugged, confidently answering, "Not really, no. Not gonna lie; you people are way out of your depths by even being here. Didn’t you hear what I said? Gods decided to fight over our planet. Beings who can blow it up with a wave of their hand. Does anyone here really think they can do shit to defend Earth? The answer is no. This is not a democratic election, either, and I bet you that after this vote, we will come to learn that there are more violent ways of attaining the title of World Leader. I hope that anyone open to being voted for is also fine with having a constant mark on them. People who are not just from Earth will come after you. That is another reason I think I am the best candidate. I welcome my would-be assassins.”

His response seemed to shut down the guy, allowing Arthur to speak up. Just as planned. "What Lord Thayne is saying is that he will act as a shield for Earth from the multiverse. Outside forces will hesitate to even have machinations on Earth due to fear of the Chosen of the Malefic Viper being the World Leader there. Assassins who would be interested in Earth would not dare risk offending the Order by attempting to assassinate him. In addition, they will refrain from killing anyone they perceive to be working for him out of fear. His role will be nearly entirely passive, and from my understanding, he will not even be on Earth the majority of the time." Arthur looked over at Jake.

"True, I will not,” Jake confirmed. “I have a multiverse to explore.”

Jake didn’t really think there needed to be more talk, but damn, was he wrong. He had been warned beforehand, but it was still annoying that it happened. Even if they had the vast majority of votes and could just vote instantly to make him World Leader once that first half an hour ended, they still freaking talked. However, the four council members had made it clear that simply brute-forcing the vote was a bad idea.

Instead, they wanted to bring everyone there on board with their decision. Jake could only sigh and sit back as he allowed the council members to show their prowess and convince everyone. The Fallen King especially had some heavy lifting to do before he would get a proper approval rating.

The only ones with good approval ratings were Arthur and, surprisingly, the Sword Saint. Arthur because of his former status and existing connections, and the Sword Saint because… well, Jake would describe it as old-man energy. Who would dare disagree with an old man’s wisdom? Plus, he just seemed authoritative whenever he spoke, making everyone subconsciously agree and take all his advice as sagely. Again, old-man powers.

Miranda was also working hard, primarily in the department of convincing everyone that while the Order was pretty damn evil by human standards, it was not the Order but Jake taking charge. She also had to explain the differences there. Everyone on the council was working damn hard.

As for Jake?

Jake was fighting the temptation to just zone it all out and do some damn alchemy as he had during all the other political events…

Luckily, it was soon time for the vote, and for Jake to finally get to see what one got out of becoming World Leader. As long as he could stay awake long enough, that is.

Chapter 70

Earth's Final Trial

After half an hour, the prompt appeared to vote for World Leader. Jake opened it and saw that it, too, was the same as every other time.

Please place your vote for World Leader of Earth. You have 10 votes and can distribute them as you desire or choose to abstain with any or all of your votes.

Votes remaining: 10/10

Time remaining: 4:29:59

Jake naturally and instantly dumped all votes on himself while the others continued talking. And damn, did they continue to talk. A lot of people just voted right away, from the looks of it, but as far as Jake could tell, the voting period would only end once all votes had been made. Jake would naturally prefer for them to just get things over with, but all he could do was wait as the negotiations happened.

In the meantime, he stood there valiantly as he, in reality, zoned out and entered his Soulspace using Serene Soul Meditation while still keeping an eye on the outside world using his sphere. In there, he discussed future matters and plans with sim-Jake for a good while until they finally finished, and in the least suspenseful vote for World Leader Jake could imagine, he got the title… which wasn’t even a damn title.

The election of World Leader has now concluded!

Results: Jake Thayne has been elected World Leader with 93% of the total votes.

Congratulations! You have been elected World Leader.

As a World Leader, you gain access to certain special privileges and abilities.

Due to the previous vote for Paths of Unusual Unions, the World Leader can formally invite native monsters of any grade into protected lands.

Allows the World Leader to announce future World Congresses.

Allows you to appoint a maximum of five (5) Ministers and delegate responsibility.

Allows the World Leader to lay claim to any area controlled by Pylons.

Allows the World Leader to…

…

More privileges and abilities will be revealed after the conclusion of Earth’s final trial if the World Leader manages to fully take control of the planet.

Jake read the many messages that popped up in front of him, but he ended up skimming most of them, as he quite frankly didn’t care about most of what they said. He adopted the same attitude as he had towards Haven. All of these things were for the council to figure out after he appointed the five Ministers and got everything delegated out.

There was also a pleasant surprise he had not expected. Jake had not thought much of the Unusual Unions vote and knew it had just resulted in some more interesting classes and professions popping up, but the positive working relationship between humans and monsters had kind of been ruined by the actions of William and Ell’Hakan. It was recovering now, but it would take time.

So to see that it had resulted in Jake gaining a very useful ability was awesome. If he read it correctly, it meant that he could now remove the restrictions C-grades had so they could go everywhere, allowing him to finally invite people like Sandy or Scarlett to Haven without any problems. That was definitely a great bonus.

Finally, there was the section about a final trial also mentioned in the welcome message to the Congress. Jake did not ponder on this much, as he could just wait for the upcoming vote that would no doubt include far more information on this trial.

He also checked and saw that his nobility title had been upgraded.

Titled Upgraded: [Nobility: Earl] --> [Nobility: Marquiss]

[Nobility: Marquiss] – A noble who has been voted World Leader and begun his true Path of planetary domination. Allows you to control several Pylons of Civilization as well as claim control of Planetary Pylons. Grants access to certain events and opportunities exclusive to nobles. Opens many new paths to power.

Jake read it through and saw some interesting things, especially the note about Planetary Pylons. If a Pylon of Civilization could claim and form a city, then the Planetary Pylon could claim a planet. It more or less functioned as the mainframe and primary controller of all other Pylons on a planet. It was kind of a natural upgrade to see, considering the message about this final trial.

All in all, not much had really changed from him becoming World Leader. Anyone with any kind of political aspirations or skills would probably vehemently disagree with him, but overall, Jake saw no real gains. He had to admit a part of him had selfishly hoped that by becoming World Leader, he would get some kind of new title or at least some passive bonus to stats or something while on the planet he supposedly led. Alas, stuff like that was probably reserved for people with social professions. If Jake had to guess, all he would really gain was another option to skip over during his evolution.

Even if it wasn’t a big deal to Jake, others seemed to disagree, as all eyes were on him. Oh… I probably have to speak again. Damn.

"Well, thanks for the vote of confidence," Jake said casually. "I will do my job, which is to stay alive and make sure no one else can claim Earth. For actual leadership, you will have to look to my Ministers. Speaking of which…"

Seeing no reason to delay, Jake turned around and instantly offered for Miranda to become a Minister. She accepted instantly, and Jake repeated this with the King, Sword Saint, and Arthur. Arthur was the only one who hesitated for a moment, but he still agreed.

"There we go—four out of five Ministers appointed," Jake said with a nod.

He knew it was common knowledge that the last member of this council would be a beast, as much of the discussion before the vote had revolved around people arguing about who to add. Most of those opposed to a beast joining the council naturally wanted someone from their own clique, or at least another human.

Valhal also had the decency to shut the fuck up during all this time, and naturally, Caleb and the Court had no interest in any kind of official position. All he did was give Jake a cheeky smile after he became World Leader, miming being so proud he had to wipe away a tear. Asshole.

They still had a few more topics to talk about, one of them being related to Valhal and a way for Jake to publicly call them out. Miranda had mentioned that he had to outwardly take a hard stance and make it clear he disapproved of what they’d done. All of it had something to do with the plans of the Viper, so Jake just rolled with it.

However, before he had a chance to… the second vote began unprompted.

The second vote of the World Congress relates to Earth’s final trial.

The enlightened species have had time to establish themselves on the planet and form alliances and connections, but will it be enough to truly lay claim to the planet as a whole? There live more than the enlightened in the multiverse, and soon Earth will have to prove it can hold up.

Chains hold back that which seeks to claim the planet as its own, but with the links broken one by one, it shall soon be released.

The Prima Guardian awaits its freedom.

To truly lay claim to planet Earth, the Planetary Pylon—a core that is currently protected by a barrier that requires two keys to open—must be claimed. One key shall be given to the elected World Leader, while the second key is held by the Prima Guardian.

However, before the Prima Guardian comes, a choice must be made.

Face your trial alone, or seek out allies.

In five years, the Guardian will arrive on Earth with its army. It must be defeated within five years of arrival, or the Guardian will move to claim the world for itself as the barrier naturally falls. All planets can choose to either engage the Prima Guardian alone or ally with others to create an army capable of defeating each planet’s Prima Guardian.

Note that the strength of each Prima Guardian is based on the number of fragments collected from slain Primas, as their Records and power have been absorbed by the Prima Guardian, as well as the overall performance of the planet in all prior system events. Rewards for slaying the Prima Guardian will be split amongst all contributing planets. Bonus reward for any planet defeating the Prima Guardian on their own. But be warned, for should the respective World Leader of any planet die, the Prima will claim the key and thus the planet.

The Prima Guardian Alliance Interface will open up for all World Leaders whose planet votes to ally with others. Should a planet choose to face its Prima Guardian alone, this interface will only appear after the World Leader’s own Prima Guardian has been defeated.

What Path will Earth walk? One where they face the Guardian by themselves, or with the help of the rest of the Milky Way?

Votes remaining: 25/25

Time remaining: 7:36:55

It was quite a chunky description that could be summed up rather easily: Big boss coming to Earth in five years, choose now to face big boss alone or ask for help like a bunch of losers. Sure, it also said that all of this was to finally claim the planet properly, but Jake cared more about the prospect of facing this Prima Guardian. He was also quite surprised by the mention of this Prima thing again.

Seems like all of that stuff about the Exalted Prima is indeed a major theme of this universe, huh? Jake thought. He had heard from the Viper that other universes had also had initiation events centered around some topic, location, or entity. However, with all initiations and all the system events that followed differing so significantly, no one could truly predict what would happen, making it all a bit more exciting. At least to Jake.

Chatter appeared around the room, bringing Jake out of his wayward thoughts and back to the World Congress chamber. Though he was unsure why people were even discussing it. He quickly placed his votes before speaking up.

"What is there to talk about?" Jake spoke loudly. "More accurately, why are all of you talking about it like it matters to you? We all know the answer already, right?"

Jake turned to the booths around him.

"If Earth truly requires aid to defeat this Prima Guardian, then no other planet in the Milky Way will be able to do anything," Caleb said, speaking up first—and omitting that there was one who did have people who could help, but no one considered that orange fuck a possibility.

"Help seems wholly unnecessary," the Sword Saint also spoke up.

"It is indeed a waste of time to even consider it," the King agreed.

"There you have it," Jake said. "So finish this damn vote already. No fucking way we are going to share our prey and bounty with other planets."

In all fairness, Jake would prefer not to share it with the others on Earth, either, but sometimes one had to be nice. Also… he saw an opportunity and leaped on it.

"Besides, the last time we invited aliens from another planet, it didn’t end well. Oh, yeah, which begs the question… Will we be able to rely on Valhal in this matter, or do we need to sign some shitty contract first before you are willing to defend Earth?" Jake said this in a venomous tone as he looked toward Sven.

Sven, to his credit, looked like he had expected this and did not try to make any excuses. "We of Valhal can only lay ourselves down flat in surrender and realize we misjudged the entire situation and made many mistakes. I thank the Chosen for showing mercy during this time so that we, with time, can make it up to you to hopefully establish a healthy and mutually beneficial working relationship, allowing us to prove ourselves to both the Chosen and Earth." Sven finished by bowing deeply.

Jake had kind of expected this, but the response did make him suspect that Sven did not know that some shady stuff was going on with the Viper’s involvement. He acted more as a CEO of a company: The board of directors did something moronic, and he now had to take responsibility. Jake would’ve felt sorry for him if not for the fact that he was still the damn CEO, and like any CEO asked to do some dumb shit, he had the option of refusing and potentially quitting. Being a heretic wasn’t that bad anyway.

"We at Valhal realize that the new World Leader and his council will need many resources to stabilize their rule, and to help this cause, Valhal is more than happy to offer gifts to expedite everything," Sven continued after a brief pause.

Did they need a lot of resources and stuff? Well, probably not, but fuck if Jake knew. What he did know was that he liked free stuff.

Staring at Sven, Jake still continued acting harshly. "You are lucky I consider the Runemaiden a close friend, or Valhal would have either gone the way of the Holy Church or the way of the alien invader’s comrades. You are on a tight leash, so don’t fuck it up. No third chances."

Sven bowed once more. "That is all we could ever ask for. Thank you, Chosen of the Malefic One."

Jake exchanged a glance with the man, feeling a sense of gratitude from him. Confronting Valhal publicly not only proved that Jake was still mad at them to everyone—including any potential spies or individuals who had a relationship with Ell’Hakan—but also allowed Valhal to apologize and get a way into the good graces of all the other factions. Many of them would have hesitated to interact with Valhal if they thought the Chosen of the Malefic Viper and his council remained pissed at them.

"Approach the council after this and discuss terms," Jake said, sweeping his gaze across the room. “For now, let’s just get this vote over with. What are you people waiting for? We are facing it alone, so place those damn votes already.”

Also, he really had to hold himself back from admonishing a lot of them some more, especially those from the United Cities Alliance. This second vote made it clear that Earth had more dangers to face, and he could already imagine the result if they had gotten their way. Jake, the King, the Sword Saint, Sylphie… So many powerful and promising individuals would have been tossed off the planet. Shit, they’d managed to make Casper leave—someone Jake would very much have liked to have around.

At least those morons seemed to listen to him now, as they finally got their shit together and placed their votes.

The election concerning the final trial of Earth has now concluded!

Earth has chosen to face the final trial alone. Your Path is set, and the Prima Guardian will descend upon the planet in five (5) years. With it shall come an army and all of the formerly undefeated Primas that have gained more power through the Seat of the Exalted Prima.

Warning: Based on collected fragments and Earth’s performance in all prior system events, the difficulty rating of the Prima Guardian is considered extremely high.

Prepare yourselves, or the Prima Guardian shall find no equal and lay claim to your world.

Jake read the message and the part about the difficulty rating. Others around him began chattering loudly again, with some mentioning how they’d made a mistake, others trying to calm them down, with a third group even asking if perhaps there was a way off Earth if things went south. Jake cared for none of it, as he could only smile to himself.

To him, it wasn’t a warning.

It was the promise of a good time.

Chapter 71

A World That Makes Sense

He had hoped it would end… but no. The World Congress was a cruel mistress and allowed them to stay within the system event for the remainder of the allotted time. Jake wanted to leave, but a sharp look from Miranda made him know that he’d better stay. Alas, it was probably for the best, as seeing the newly elected World Leader run away prematurely probably didn’t inspire confidence.

However, even if he was forced to stay physically, no one had told him to not go on a mental journey to somewhere better. Even if he did try to stay engaged and at least feign interest. Hey, he had tried, okay?

Jake would firmly classify the rest of the World Congress as a waste of time. Miranda would probably disagree and call it a "valuable opportunity to calm the doubters and display unity to the many City Lords of Earth, thus inspiring confidence in the council."

In fact, those had been the exact words she used.

Anyway, Jake had nearly eight hours to listen to mundane chatter, and by the time the subject of tax codes was brought up, Jake completely zoned out and went into his Soulspace to talk to a way better conversation partner: himself.

Within his Soulspace, sim-Jake and the cursed chimera both sat calmly, and sim-Jake had a hand on the huge monster. It did not react, instead letting him stay there, and Jake knew what he was doing. Some kind of attunement. The details were still a bit fuzzy, but Jake knew that the curse energy and Eternal Hunger were instrumental to the mythical-rarity skill he and sim-Jake hoped to make.

After waiting a while, sim-Jake was done, and the moment he released his hand, the huge beast of pure curse energy attacked, forcing sim-Jake to seal it again. Once that was done, Jake’s other self turned around and regarded him.

"This entire deal with World Leader is a waste of time," sim-Jake said, commenting on recent events. "Why bother? Just evacuate everyone to the Order of the Malefic Viper and leave this stupid rock behind. All you are doing is creating distractions for us."

"Maybe, maybe not." Jake shrugged. "In either case, I don’t plan on making it into a distraction, but an opportunity. We don’t know what benefits being World Leader may offer in the future, but I am willing to risk it leading to nothing for the chance to gain something unique."

"And if it doesn’t?"

"Then I will have wasted a bit of time. How much lifespan do we have by now? Do you even know? I reckon at least a thousand years or something, and probably ten times that at C-grade. So what is a few years chasing a bad lead?"

"Ultimately, the choice is yours." Sim-Jake shrugged. "You are the one who will have to deal with all of the annoyances. I just don’t want you to dilly-dally and end up stuck at S-grade because you decided to fuck around and not focus on what truly matters."

"If I get stuck at S-grade, I will just have to hunt a few gods or something," Jake said with a grin, unafraid. "Or die trying. Both are acceptable."

Sim-Jake just shook his head. "Anyway, we will need a lot of time to prepare, and especially with this Prima Guardian arriving… do we have time? Can you figure something out with the Viper?"

Jake nodded. "Should definitely be able to. Once we go to the Order, we can look into it. But you are certain that this Path you have chosen to walk down will work?"

His other self just smiled. "I am betting my entire existence on it."

Everything was wrong. At least, it had been. Suddenly, everything looked so clear, the muddiness of reality washed away as the many strings that held William down were forcefully severed by the system itself.

He felt so weird he had a hard time describing it. He had joined the World Congress after having practically been ordered to, not sure what he could even get out of it. He had spent the last month just wandering around, unsure of where to go and what to do. Ms. Kim had told him that maybe being lost and working on finding himself for a while wasn’t the worst, but William hated feeling so… wrong.

Quite a few times, he regretted wanting more emotions that much, but in the end, he knew it was for the best. It just sucked to feel like he was walking through a swamp, as though the endless threads of karma around him were a net made to slow him down and incapacitate him.

That is, until he joined the World Congress. In an instant, the threads disappeared. The net was gone, clarity washed through his mind, and he even felt like his body underwent a cleansing. That was when he realized why the Chosen of the Malefic Viper had wanted him to enter the World Congress.

In the Congress, nothing could influence him… and all ongoing influence was dispelled. While William could not be sure, he had a fear that Eversmile had placed several karmic magics on him that denouncing the Blessing did nothing to address.

Yet, even with his mind clear, it only became more evident how truly lost he was. William was still afraid of the Chosen, yes, but it wasn’t the same kind of fear… In fact, standing there in the World Congress, he had no particularly negative feelings. It made William wonder if the intense fear had ever been his own, or just the result of Eversmile doing something.

William had slept once during this month as a test, and for the first time since the tutorial, he didn’t have a nightmare. That at least somewhat confirmed that the cause of his nightmares—all of which just amplified his fear of the Chosen—was not natural in any way.

Hearing the speech of the Chosen also made William realize one thing: The Chosen truly didn’t care about a lot of things, and he probably didn’t care about William at all, either, unless he made direct trouble for him. It was comforting but also disturbing, as William realized that the strongest emotion he could detect towards himself using his karmic magic wasn’t anger or killing intent. It was apathy. An emotion he realized the Chosen had also had before their last encounter…

William simply wasn’t a noteworthy character in the eyes of the Chosen of the Malefic Viper. At most, he was a curiosity to the man. Their disparity in power was large, and seeing people like the Sword Saint and the King around him only made it all the more evident how insignificant William truly was.

It made it clear that William, indeed, wasn’t a protagonist of the world as he had gone around thinking for so long. The Chosen was one. The Sword Saint. The Fallen King. But William? William was just a karmic mage who could hopefully one day be helpful to all the people he’d screwed over. He realized this and could only smile to himself.

A huge weight lifted from his shoulders, as he was finally free of the endless net of toxic karma and pressure. He wasn’t really anyone special… and he didn’t need to be. He just had to be who he wanted to be and do what he himself wanted to do. Find out what he actually wanted out of life.

Race Evolution Quest

As you reach the end of D-grade, you have walked a Path seeking perfection. A Path of discovery of yourself and what you want to be. Yet you have not found it. Without determination and vision, there is no Path. Without desire, there is no progress. Without willingness, there is no life.

Objective: Find your Path (1/1)

*Race Evolution Requirements Met*

WARNING: Evolution unavailable during ongoing system event.

William saw the system message as the quest completed, and he could only sigh at how stupidly simple some things could be.

--

Jake’s escape was glorious. He teleported back to Earth after seven damn hours of super engaging political discussions that sometimes disturbed his and sim-Jake’s far more interesting conversation. Sadly, he went straight from the pan and into the fire, as he had another damn meeting at the main office of Haven just after the World Congress. The Sword Saint, King, and Miranda had been teleported back to where they had entered from, so at least they were all gathered again right away.

More politics. More talking. Luckily, Jake quickly managed to find an excuse to sneak off, but just before he did so, the old man at the table asked for a bit of his time.

The Sword Saint led Jake into another room and erected an isolation barrier around them. Jake wondered what it was about until the old man explained, "I have considered matters more related to this entire situation with Ell’Hakan. From what I gathered, I believe others here have a misunderstanding. Jake, when you fought him, how powerful did you think he was? How would you evaluate him?"

Jake considered for a moment. "Elusive, fast, resilient, but overall not a major threat in direct combat. He mainly used his goons against me and took more of a supportive role as a caster. Don’t get me wrong—he is strong for his level, but he is a pompous dick using tricks over power."

The old man nodded. "Did you think he faced you seriously at the time?"

After thinking for a few seconds, Jake shook his head. "No, definitely not. His plan was always to throw me to the other side of the planet, and he was just buying time."

"Interestingly enough, I got the same feeling when he fought me," the Sword Saint said. "At least in the beginning. However, as time passed, he did have a genuine desire to kill me. We fought for longer and more seriously than you did. Is that assertion correct?"

Jake nodded. "True. What are you trying to say?"

"While it is a cliche, I do believe one can learn a lot about someone from fighting them. My understanding of this Ell’Hakan, from all the explanations before I encountered him, was that we were dealing with a politician born with a golden spoon. Yet when I fought him, I met something entirely different. I met a seasoned fighter who has wielded his weapon for decades. A warrior born through slaughter. He also enjoyed our fight far too much, even refraining from using his Bloodline for nearly the entire fight."

"So he is stronger than I initially thought? Does it ultimately matter?"

"No, perhaps it does not. But I do feel like I need to warn you. Do not underestimate Ell’Hakan in battle, even if you manage to isolate and fight him alone. While our battle did appear to end with my victory, I had far from won. He still had far more to show me, and he was far too calm. I truly believe now that without inviting springtime fully, I would have died if we had kept fighting. So do not mistake his schemes as a sign of weakness, as I fear that when he is backed into a corner without any schemes, he becomes the most dangerous. Less annoying, perhaps, but more deadly."

If it was anyone else saying all this, Jake could have probably brushed them off or maybe even considered that Ell’Hakan had messed with their heads. However, this was the Sword Saint, probably the human Jake respected the most as an equal. If he thought Ell’Hakan was more than met the eye, he could only take it to heart.

"Got it," Jake said with a serious nod. He still firmly believed he was stronger than Ell’Hakan, barring any tricks or schemes, and he would keep thinking that until the orange fucker proved him wrong or was dead. But… there was a chance that the gap was not as large as Jake believed.

"That is all I wanted to add," the Sword Saint said. “Now, continue your journey. I shall remain here a bit before I, too, head out and finish the final steps before my evolution.”

"Good luck with it all," Jake said, smiling as he headed off back toward the lodge. Carmen joined him shortly on the walk back, looking deep in thought.

When they reached the lodge, she finally spoke. "Do you think I made a mistake by joining Valhal?" she asked, a bit unsure. "Fuck, even asking that is being a heretic, isn’t it?"

Jake looked at her and shrugged. "If they consider that heretical, then fuck ’em. Besides, I doubt they do. And I would not say you made a mistake; quite the opposite. They fit you. Just ignore all of the political shit like I do. I don’t blame you for what Valhal chooses to do as long as you don’t blame me for whatever nefarious shit the Order of the Malefic Viper is up to."

Carmen smirked. "A bit unfair, considering you are the Chosen, but sure. Does feel weird to dedicate kills to them and do stuff in their honor, though."

"Just think about doing it for Valdemar. Valdemar is a cool dude, as far as I can tell. Or just dedicate kills to the concept of Valhal. There are plenty of ways to make the Path you walk make sense to you. Worst case, just become a heretic who doesn’t actually believe in anything Valhal does but still wants their skills and Records." Jake shrugged. "I am really not the one to ask advice from for things like this—you do know that, right?"

"Or maybe you are," Carmen said, sighing. "Either way, I want to do some soul-searching, I guess. By soul-searching, I mean wander into the forest and kill shit alone until the world makes more sense to me, or I have at least punched all my frustrations out."

"Totally fair," Jake said. "Killing things is a great way to clear your mind. Very zen."

Carmen shook her head and punched him in the shoulder. "Say goodbye to Sylphie for me. I don’t really wanna delay but just head out right away. Before that cute little ball of feathers makes me want to stay."

"Have fun." Jake waved to her, as she had already begun heading off. Within a few seconds, she was out of the valley and headed toward the forest. Wait, what if she kills all the good prey? Well… I guess I can share a bit.

Jake used his bond to search for Sylphie and realized she was somewhere far up in the sky. Really far up. Not quite at the layer of C-grades, but close. If he had to guess, he would say the small hawk was showing off to her parents.

Referring to his checklist of things to do before C-grade, Jake now only had four things left to do before evolving. Besides getting those last few class levels, of course. Though he could do that pretty quickly after he was done with all the other things he wanted to do.

1. Upgrade Sagacity of the Malefic Viper.

2. Go to Order and defeat baby Snappy.

3. Mythical skill creation with the help of sim-Jake.

4. Actually evolve.

Jake had checked off two things, and he planned to achieve all his remaining goals—besides the evolution itself—at the Order. But before going, he had to do one more thing he did not add to his list. Becoming World Leader had not really given him much value, but there had been one useful benefit.

The ability to allow C-grades to visit human areas.

Seeing Sylphie was gone, Jake headed straight for the Mangrove River—this time not to visit them, but to allow Scarlett to visit him. Then, afterward, he could head up and say hi to Sandy and also allow his worm friend to go wherever they wanted. Finally, he would see if he could have a certain whale visit.

Because what could possibly go wrong by bringing a group of powerful C-grades into an occupied human city?

Chapter 72

Snake in the City

To call Scarlett absolutely ecstatic that Jake had visited so fast again was an understatement. It only got more extreme when Jake asked her to help out with his experiment of allowing her to follow him to otherwise restricted areas.

"So, I will admit, I am not entirely certain how this works," Jake said. He did not have a skill or anything to "mark" people. Well, he did have one to mark people, but that was something else entirely. The World Leader ability was weird, and Jake tried to do the most basic stuff.

He concentrated and willed for Scarlett to be allowed to go anywhere. Nothing seemed to happen, and Jake feared that he couldn’t actually use this ability without a profession allowing it or a lot of practice. Yet after a few seconds, Scarlett spoke up.

"I… I think it worked?" she said, a bit unsure and nervous.

"And you are not just saying that because I want it to work and for me to feel better?" Jake asked skeptically.

"I would never do… I… No… I do feel a bit different,” Scarlett said, still as nervous as before. “It is weird, and I can’t quite explain it, but I feel more… free? Unburdened?"

"Have you tried using a teleporter before?" Jake then asked her.

"I have.” She nodded. "But only ones within the Mangrove when Old Grumpy was experimenting. I cannot use the teleporters the humans set up to travel outside of my domain."

"Out of curiosity, what stops you? You being C-grade, or the system restrictions?"

"I do not know; it just simply doesn’t allow me to travel through." Scarlett shook her head. A moment passed before her eyes lit up. "Oh! You mean to say that maybe it would work now?"

"That is the hope," Jake said, smirking. "Willing to give it a shot? If not, and you are hit with some kind of backlash, you should be able to instantly teleport back again. Though it is a bit risky, and we could maybe just go to the outskirts of the Mangrove."

"I trust the Chosen." Scarlett smiled. "And I am certain the system would not allow me to teleport if it would simply result in my demise."

Jake was still a bit apprehensive, but Scarlett had clearly made up her mind. Seeing her determination, he could only agree, and they walked to the teleporter together. With several C-grade snakes watching curiously, the two of them went into the teleportation chamber.

He saw how nervous she was, making him reach out and hold her hand—with gloves on, of course—as he smiled comfortingly at her. "Are you ready?"

Her otherwise ghostly white face flushed red as she offered a small nod. They activated the teleporter, and Jake still held onto the hand as they appeared at the Fort. An entire snake girl was attached to the hand, too, and she appeared perplexed for a moment before looking around her.

Jake, still holding her hand, led her outside. They hadn’t appeared far from the giant metal dome, with a great outlook over the city that had sprung up at the Fort. And, honestly, it really was a city at this point. Jake had no idea how many people lived there—despite owning the land—but he knew it had to be a lot. It was turning into a real metropolis.

Scarlett seemed to barely register that he still held her hand. Her head whipped from side to side, her reptilian eyes darting around to take in everything. Jake smiled and felt happy for her.

Turning his head, he also looked towards a certain spot in mid-air and gave a nod. An invisible drone that had been floating there stopped observing them and moved on, and Jake also felt the attention of dozens of other similar observers leaving him. Arnold sure had some protection set up in the Fort, from the looks of it.

"What do you say?" Jake asked.

"It is… large,” she said. “So many humans in one place, yet all of them are so weak. The weak are protected by the strong. Hunting others is disallowed, too, right? Doesn’t that mean most who live here are creators and not fighters?"

"It is mostly creators, but remember that they are not to be underestimated. Within that metal dome is one of the most dangerous humans on Earth, and he is a pure creator." Jake then pointed out Arnold’s mad-scientist lair.

"A strong construction—the metal looks nearly as resilient as my scales," she said, impressed. Not realizing that it said more about her damn scales than a giant dome of metal. The worst part was that Jake also estimated it to be the truth, if not an understatement to praise Arnold.

"Just don’t begin to go around destroying stuff to test that out," Jake joked.

"I would never!" Scarlett said with much indignation. She shook her head and tried to raise her hands, but her movement made her aware she was still holding onto Jake’s hand, making her quiet down and look at the ground.

Jake just shook his head and softly let go of her hand. "Let’s head back to Haven, okay?"

She stared at this hand with disappointment for a moment before nodding. "If that is what the Chosen wants."

Will really have to work on that attitude before we get to the Order, Jake thought, but he didn’t say much as he headed out of the Fort with Scarlett. The two of them flew, and Jake had to admit that even with him using wings and Scarlett just flying with regular energy manipulation, she was still far faster than him. He didn’t doubt that she could destroy pretty much any human settlement on Earth if she so desired.

Once they made their way back to Haven, Jake led Scarlett toward the lodge. Miranda and the others were still stuck in the office discussing stuff, so he would have to leave her alone for a bit with his banana tree-that-wasn’t-a-tree.

"Can you wait here for a while?" Jake asked her once they made it to the lodge.

Scarlett seemed disappointed again but still looked around curiously, prompting Jake to explain a bit about where they were. "This is my lodge and pretty much my home on Earth. It’s where I first started to live after I returned from the tutorial, and it has a lot of sentimental value.”

Scarlett’s eyes opened wide, and she seemed to look at the lodge with far different eyes. She closely studied everything, yet soon noted something. "Someone dared break the Chosen’s table!?"

Jake cringed a bit and scratched his head. "An… accident happened. Anyway, see you in a bit!"

With a jump, Jake headed toward the sky to gather even more beast friends. Sylphie and family were all up there, and while Sandy was probably nowhere close, he had a strong feeling they could get to him pretty damn fast. To make sure his sand worm friend wasn’t too slow, he took out the weird egg-that-wasn’t-an-egg and infused some energy into it during his ascent. Once he felt like Sandy had noticed, he stopped and stored the egg away again.

Finally, he contacted a certain someone to set up a meeting. Jake reached out mentally as the divine connection descended.

"Well, well, well, I guess a congratulation is in order, revered World Leader of Earth," Villy immediately joked. "I can’t even begin to tell you how proud I am, seeing you move up in the world and become a proper politician."

"Fuck off," Jake joked back. "I guess I should also say I am proud of you for holding back your curiosity and not contacting me right after my most recent vision into your controversial past."

"No need to give me credit; I just had more important things to do. I was actually doing alchemy, you know? Duskleaf is over the moon." Villy was clearly grinning on the other side.

"Funny, because in this vision, you were also doing alchemy and being rather shit at it. Couldn’t even make a health potion.”

"Hey, my failures paved the way to greatness," Villy said, taking it in stride as they finally got down to business. "So, another one of these World Congresses is over with. Anything worth sharing?"

"Well, we got this upcoming final trial thing…"

Jake began to explain the second vote in detail, pretty much just reading what the system messages had said. The Prima Guardian would appear in five years, but as they both interpreted it, then they only really had to fight the Prima within ten. Five or ten years wasn’t a lot of time, but it also wasn’t a little. He did wonder about one thing, though…

"Do you think this Prima Guardian will be B-grade?" Jake asked curiously.

"If it is, your entire planet is doomed, and you might as well bail now," Villy mocked him back. "Even with Nevermore, reaching B-grade or a level where you can hunt B-grades within five or even ten years is utterly unfeasible. The time you can spend in Nevermore is still limited, and even if you did choose to just rush levels, you would be hit hard by diminishing returns. If you did somehow manage to make it to a level of power where you could fight B-grades in time, it would be with a shitty foundation and sorely lacking Records for a C-grade. So, no, at most, this Prima Guardian will be in the later stages of C-grade. I have never heard of any B-grade in any of these initiation events appearing within a decade."

Jake took it all in and nodded in understanding, but he did bite onto one thing. "Are the diminishing returns really that bad? Isn’t it only really a thing if you hunt a lot of the same kind of enemy, or if the fights get too easy? I haven’t noticed it otherwise, I don’t think.”

“It is bad, yes," Villy began, being the great god of exposition he was. “So far, you have not really had many issues with it, sure, but that doesn’t mean it won’t happen in the future. For the tutorial, it is by design not a problem, and after returning to Earth, you have had a natural and balanced approach. If you had decided to go dungeon hunting in rapid succession after you cleared that one below your city, or maybe went in to explore the forest right away, you would have gained some more levels, yes, but soon you would’ve found the levels just stopped coming all together, or it would’ve gotten to the point where you could kill a thousand beasts higher level than you and still not level up. It happens to many who try to rush their levels and not focus on other things. In fact, it happens to everyone to some degree, as it kicks in after a single kill granting experience. You can alleviate this issue with qualitative upgrades along the way, like skill upgrades, but it can only do so much. The best thing to do is simply wait and focus on other pursuits. Even beasts have to do this—hence why they rarely hunt, but instead consume natural treasures to slowly progress or work on improving other qualitative aspects of themselves. Ah, but I would note that there are windows of sorts. The start of any grade is one such window where you can do a shitload of hunting without running into any noteworthy issues.”

"Huh,” Jake said. “I assume that last part is why a lot of the Nevermore stuff is at early C-grade only?"

"Exactly," Villy confirmed. "It is a great chance to get some solid levels under your belt for all of you earthlings. Shit, it may even be expected by the system that you will go to Nevermore and gain levels to face this Prima Guardian thing."

"Aight. Two more things. First, do you think this event is part of Ell’Hakan and Yip’s plan?"

"When?" Villy asked a bit teasingly.

"When what?"

"When do you think it might’ve become a part of their plan? If you mean before the World Congress, then no. No one knew what event would take place. If you mean right now, then yes, it will certainly be factored into their schemings. That is the hallmark of any good plan: adaptability. You do not expect everything to go flawlessly, but adapt and reconfigure the plan to still reach an acceptable outcome. Now, what was your second question?"

"Eh, could you help contact that Karroch god for me so I can find the whale he blessed? I want to talk to it about potentially being in the council.”

"You want me to reach out to some weak, unaffiliated god and ask him for a favor?" Villy asked with disdain. “To be the one who approaches him first, laying down my pride?”

"Or send someone else?" Jake scratched his head. "Or a letter?"

"A possibility," Villy said teasingly. "But I must actually hand it to this Karroch. Out of all the gods not close to me, he is probably the one who knows most about our relationship just from the fact that he was in charge of your tutorial. His plan of trying to help you to get in my good graces is quite well thought-out."

"Is it working?" Jake teased back.

"A little. I tend to not be a fan of beastmasters, if I am perfectly honest. He was very unpopular before due to having made quite a few enemies, especially the Brimstone Hegemon, who I happened to kill. He should be able to find other Pantheons who want him, but I guess I can reach out with an olive branch for my dear Chosen and offer him a job. From what I saw, he at least seemed like one of the less shitty beastmasters around.”

"Thank you, oh, my ever-benevolent Patron," Jake answered with much reverence.

"Yeah, fuck you, and see you at the Order soon!" Villy then promptly cut the connection.

Jake just smirked and kept flying until he finally reached far enough up for C-grades to live.

He could get Sylphie and family on the way down once he had gathered Sandy, as he had a strong feeling that making them wait for him wasn’t gonna work out well. Sylphie was not known to be the most patient of birds.

However, it appeared the choice was not his to make when he felt the green bird approach from afar, likely dragging her parents along based on her slower speed. Jake had stopped just at the C-grade cloud layer, where he sat himself down on a platform of mana in mid-air and stared out into the clouds. He saw movement in the distance but didn’t bother with beasts unless they decided to mess with him first.

Minutes passed as Sylphie grew closer. She had been quite a bit away and wasn’t in a rush, seemingly even taking breaks—or having fights—along the way. He also got the feeling that Sandy was on their way, quite a lot faster than the hawks could possibly travel.

Smiling a bit to himself, Jake decided to meditate a bit as he waited for the beasts to arrive. Hopefully, they would get along.

Chapter 73

A Friend of a Friend is a Rival

They did not get along.

Well, more accurately, Sylphie seemed to not get along with Sandy in the slightest. She zoomed around Sandy, making angry noises as her blades of wind tried to harm the giant worm. Sandy, in turn, just laughed.

"He he, the little bird tickles!"

Jake just shook his head and smiled. Sylphie probably could do some real damage if she wanted, but she at least had enough awareness to hold back. Then again, Sandy could also just leave in a heartbeat if Sylphie became a bit too much.

Hawkie and Mystie just stared at the giant worm that wriggled in the air from the constant assault of the peak D-grade hawk. An assault that would tear most D-grades to shreds in seconds, even if it was just Sylphie playing.

Sandy kept laughing as they asked, "So… So you said I can now go anywhere? I did feel something when you focused real hard before."

"That is how things should be," Jake answered. "Give it a go?"

"Sure!"

In the next moment, Sandy disappeared, leaving an even angrier Sylphie behind to miss her blows. Jake frowned when he felt the ripples of space from where the giant worm had just been. A moment later, Sandy popped their head out of the clouds below. "It works!"

Jake opened his mouth to speak, then ended up just shaking his head again. "Let’s visit Haven, then. There is someone else I want you both to meet."

He spoke telepathically out loud so both the hawks and Sandy could hear it, even if he knew Sandy could also hear him if he spoke normally. Sylphie, hearing this, looked at Sandy with a challenging gaze before flying towards Jake with great speed, right into his arms. Jake reacted on instinct and caught her. She nuzzled up to his chest and got herself comfortable, still throwing looks at Sandy.

"I think your bird is jealous," Sandy joked with him. "Ah, but I get it! Wind magic is kind of just worse space magic, isn’t it? Must feel inferior. Poor thing."

Sylphie took great offense to this, screeching, "Ree! Ree!"

"Oh, you got super wind? Well, I got super cosmic space! No! Genesis cosmic space!"

Sylphie momentarily looked taken aback but soon retaliated. "Ree!"

This time, Sandy seemed to have taken a hit, as Sylphie brilliantly argued that space was just boring wind, and as her wind was kind of green, it was superior to space magic in all ways, since space didn’t have a color. An argument Jake had no idea even made sense. Especially as Sandy then began to argue that colors actually made things worse…

Which just made even less sense, as Sandy had no eyes and couldn’t see colors.

I may have made a mistake, Jake realized as he led the two arguing beasts down toward his lodge. He did notice one issue there, though. Sandy was a bit… big. Could probably find a place to lay in the valley, but it would be problematic to bring them around anywhere.

Jake voiced his concern, which Sylphie just took as ammunition to argue she was superior. However, this time around, she had to admit defeat.

"Oh, yeah? Well, space magic is so cool it can do stuff like this!"

In an instant, Sandy’s body began to shrink. Jake felt the intense movements of space mana doing the work, and Jake knew that Sandy technically wasn’t getting smaller; they just compressed the space around themselves and created a pocket of sorts. Jake knew that a good wave of destructive mana would destroy this technique, and it probably also took quite the upkeep, but he nevertheless gave Sandy a thumbs-up.

Sylphie tried to puff herself up by breathing in as much as she could, hoping to make herself look bigger to prove she could also grow in size, but this ultimately just made her look silly. Sandy laughed in triumph as they, now about the size of a large horse, flew down next to Jake. Quite a bit slower than before, mind you. This only hammered home that the impromptu shrinking technique had little to no practical application outside of letting Sandy fit into spaces they previously couldn’t.

Soon the valley entered their sight, and Jake frowned, as he didn’t see Scarlett anywhere. Upon landing, he also didn’t see her anywhere within the house. Jake wondered if she had gone to explore the laboratory below the lodge. Rather than wondering, Jake closed his eyes and activated tracking as well as his usual sensing abilities.

She went down to the biodome?

As Jake wondered what had attracted her there, he motioned for the group of birds and worm to follow. On the way, Sylphie managed to zoom over and swipe a newly formed banana, making Jake shake his head at the audacity of these fruit thieves.

They quickly went down and into the cave, which Sandy complimented as feeling very nice and familiar. Once a sand worm, always a sand worm, it seemed. Jake felt Scarlett ahead, and upon entering the biodome, he saw her walking behind a large troll that motioned to different plants with three smaller trolls following behind.

"What you doing?" Jake asked once he got closer.

Scarlett turned around and bowed, with Rick also turning and doing a big wave.

"I was simply receiving teachings from Sir Rick," Scarlett said. "He tends the garden of the Chosen, does he not?"

"That he does, and he is doing a damn good job, too," Jake said with a smile, giving Rick a big thumbs-up. Rick mimicked Jake and did a thumbs-up back with an even bigger smile.

Jake wasn’t lying, either. He really liked the biodome. Did he actually use the garden down there? No, not really. In fact, he had kind of forgotten about it and all of his plans for it, including the artificial sun he’d wanted to install and all that jazz.

At least Jake now realized that maybe that sun would have been a bad idea, as Rick seemed to do best with underground plants anyway. However, even if Jake didn’t use the underground garden much, it didn’t make it useless. He could always sell what grew there or maybe use it to help train new alchemists or something. Or, well, to just have Rick have a nice place to live and enjoy life.

"Ree!" Sylphie screeched, finally making herself known. Not that Scarlett hadn’t noticed the entourage, which consisted of three hawks and a large, floating worm. Sylphie seemed to have found yet another rival as she stared up at Scarlett, who stared back.

For a moment, Jake got the feeling that Scarlett was jealous of Sylphie? He looked down at the hawk cradled in his arms, not sure why she would be.

“Greetings, hawk of wind,” Scarlett said, also looking at Hawkie, Mystie, and Sandy. “Hawk of lighting, of mysticism, and worm of… space?”

“Eh, acceptable assessment,” Sandy answered. “Nice to meet you too, white snake!”

Hawkie and Mystie both regarded Scarlett with apprehension as they felt her power. As a mid-tier C-grade, she was by far the strongest among them, and they all knew it. If she was an enemy, they would all be in deep shit, with even Sandy having difficulties. If anyone could get away, it would be the worm, though.

"Anyway, I guess I should introduce you all…"

Jake did the polite thing and had all his beast friends get to know each other. Rick also joined in, very interested in having guests. He even brought over some interesting-looking fruits Jake did not recognize, but found to taste extremely good.

On a side note, no one mentioned that Sandy also happened to be the Chosen of Snappy, or the Boundless Hydra, as fancy people called him. Not doing so was probably a good idea, as Jake was entirely uncertain how Scarlett would react, and it would also ruin one of the best things Jake had seen in a while…

A worm, a snake, and a hawk arguing which race was best. Scarlett argued snakes were just better worms, Sandy vehemently disagreed and came up with weird arguments for worms being the best, and Sylphie kept screeching how hawks were the "bestest."

Hawkie and Mystie even backed up their daughter with information on how birds—hawks included—had actually hunted both worms and snakes before the system. Scarlett, however, also had memories of before the system and talked about how snakes had eaten the eggs of stupid birds who just left them lying around… causing Sandy to then say that worms didn’t care, as worms just ate anything, thus proving they were the best beasts in existence.

Now, it was only after Jake gathered all these beasts together that he finally got around to asking a pertinent question: why?

Why had he gathered them all in Haven? Scarlett was here to bring her to the Order, but did he need to call for Sandy and allow the worm to travel into human territory? Well, no, he didn’t have to. Sandy probably wouldn’t even like being in human territory due to the lack of tasty things to eat.

So, why? The simple answer was just that Jake had wanted to. He wanted to, at the very least, give the beasts the freedom to go wherever they wanted. It was funny how his mind had instantly made granting them more freedom of movement a priority despite the lack of practical merit.

Also… he had to admit that seeing them all like this was amusing. Sylphie had long left his arms to fly around and argue louder while chasing Sandy. Scarlett, in turn, tried really hard to look dignified while three kid trolls poked her and tried to touch her snakeskin dress.

Eventually, they did get tired of their squabbles, and Jake could finally get to the important part after they at least chimed down a little.

"Scarlett and I will be headed to the Order of the Malefic Viper, and while we are going, I would at least like to offer you all the opportunity to come with," Jake said to the group.

"Meh, I’m good here—still stuff to eat," Sandy said, instantly shutting it down. "And the many-headed guy says that staying on Earth is also all good, so I stay."

Rick shook his head, understanding the sentiment but seemingly happy where he was. Hawkie and Mystie also declined—something Jake had expected.

"Ree!" Sylphie explained, expertly outlining why she wouldn’t go.

"Guess it will just be us going, then, Scarlett." Jake smiled at the snake girl.

"Yes!" She nodded happily. "I once more thank the Chosen for giving me this—"

“But before that,” he interrupted, “we must work on that.”

"Work on what?" Scarlett asked, confused and nervous.

"You see… I am hiding that I am the Chosen at the Order for several reasons, so you need to not publicly recognize me as such. To not slip up by accident, it would be best if you got used to calling me something else. Something less… formal.”

"I… I could use My Excellence?" Scarlett tried, though it looked to hurt her to use such an "informal" term.

Jake scratched the back of his head. "Yeah… again, some problems there. It wouldn’t make any sense. We both got a Blessing, and the one I am hiding my True Blessing to make it look not that high, so you speaking to me like an authority makes little sense."

Scarlett looked lost for words, just staring at him.

"It would be best if you could just call me by my name…"

He saw the poor snake girl’s head turn red, and her eyes went wide as she looked just about to melt down.

"… or maybe just call me Lord Thayne still?" Jake said, trying to save it.

After a while, Scarlett collected herself. "I…"

"Heh! Silly snake! Hey, Jake, she sure is bad at using names, right, Jake? You see, Jake and I are friends, so I can call him Jake, and he can call me Sandy!" The cosmic worm was clearly bragging to Scarlett while wriggling proudly.

Scarlett clenched her fists. "I—I can also call him… Ja… Lord Thayne!"

It looked like merely uttering the sentence had taken more energy than slaying a hundred C-grades for the poor snake girl. She looked nervously at Jake, who just smiled at her while mentally giving Sandy a high-five for the assist. Not that he was sure Sandy had intended to help and not just make fun of Scarlett.

"Should we get going, then?" Jake asked.

Scarlett nodded with delight as Sandy also decided to follow them. Sylphie quickly headed off again with her parents, only telling Jake that she wanted to evolve soon but "make better friends with the wind” first.

Rick, of course, stayed in his cave. He was a cave troll, after all. A cave troll gardener close to C-grade.

Jake did not need to say goodbye to anyone else. Primarily because he could just head home within five or ten minutes if need be.

The trip back to the Mangrove was fast and easy, and they quickly headed down to the formation below the Mangrove, where the snake Scarlett called Old Grumpy was still hard at work. On the way, Sandy commented about how funny teleportation circles were… while at the same time talking about how easy it would be to mess with them.

Once they made it down to the large underground tunnel, however, Sandy shut up. The Genesis Cosmic Worm looked lost as they stared at the runes on the walls and began to move around.

"This is… awesome," Sandy said, wriggling closer to a specific wall with a bunch of runes. "So cool! Oh! This one does that? Wha… Wait… ah! Yeah, that makes sense… but why does the dust move like…"

The worm was utterly engrossed as Old Grumpy made his way over. "I greet the Chosen and the Mistress. Have you come to make use of the teleporter?"

Jake nodded. "That we have. You said I was ready, right?"

"Indeed! Please follow me… but what is that creature you brought along?" Old Grumpy asked.

Said worm whipped around as fast as a super-shrunken space worm could. "Hi! I am Sandy! Did you make this place?"

The old snake considered the worm for a moment before bowing. "I cannot take credit for such a feat; it is all through the guidance of the Malefic One. It gladdens me to encounter one who surpasses myself. May I know if thee have any criticisms?"

"I wanted to ask you for stuff!" Sandy responded in a very happy tone.

"Let’s get us teleported, and then you two can chat, eh?" Jake said with a smile, happy to see Sandy able to get along with another beast.

"As the Chosen wills," Old Grumpy answered, leading them to the central chamber.

Once they stood on it, the old snake did some stuff, and Jake felt the formation hum to life. Sandy looked on during it all, interested and even making some small comments here and there.

The connection to the First Universe through the void formed and strengthened. Jake sensed his True Blessing and potent karmic connection to the Malefic Viper functioning as the catalyst to allow the teleportation.

He reached out and held Scarlett’s hand to make sure she was brought along. Just as they were about to be swept away, Jake heard Sandy make one last comment.

"Oh! It uses the True Blessing! Does that mean I could use it with my True Blessing from the Boundless Hydra after some modifications?"

And Jake nearly broke his hand from Scarlett tensing up as they teleported back to the Order.

Chapter 74

Back to School Season

Man, who would have ever thought that one could miss school? Jake had even leaned into tropes by bringing a transfer student along…

A transfer student that was frozen in panic even as she and Jake appeared in the grassy area outside of his way-too-large mansion in the Order of the Malefic Viper. Jake’s hand was squeezed so hard he had no way of releasing it as poor Scarlett tried to process everything.

"I… Is… Is the worm the…?" Scarlett stammered out nervously.

"Chosen of Snappy? Yep," Jake confirmed casually. "Ah, but keep that a secret, too. I haven’t really discussed it with Sandy, but we may as well keep it hidden."

"Wi… Will—"

"No, Sandy does not give a flying fuck about any kind of perceived disrespect or whatever," Jake answered, already knowing what the poor snake girl wanted to ask. Spending so much time with Miranda really hadn’t done her much good on that front, as she now knew far more about the Order and the structure, as well as how important of a character the Lord Protector was.

Scarlett looked like she was about to ask more when movement came from within the mansion. Jake looked over and smiled as a familiar face peeked her head out. The elf’s eyes opened wide once she saw him.

"Lord Thayne!" she yelled, quickly running out and over to him. Jake noticed her level had grown yet again—and quite fast, too.

[Elf – lvl 163]

"It’s been too long," Jake said, waving at her.

Scarlett also finally let go of his hand and stared at the elven woman running over with a frown. Meira barely seemed to notice the snake girl as she stopped a few steps from Jake.

"Welcome back to the Order, Lord Thayne!" she said with a deep bow and a smile.

Jake smiled as she just stood there. She didn’t ask why he had left so suddenly back when Ell’Hakan had invaded, but would wait for him to tell her himself. If he wanted to tell her. Coupled with her progress, Jake also saw she had tended to things properly when she looked over to a certain spot on the lawn. Quite a large spot, as the grass had been cleared, replaced by a large formation with an object placed in the middle: a large boulder of sorts with holes in it.

It was the Pollendust Bee Queen ritual circle. Jake had not forgotten it, and he was glad to see that Meira hadn’t either.

"Are things progressing well with the circle?" Jake asked Meira as he looked at it.

"Yes, my Lord! In your absence, I took the initiative and acquired some extra cores when I ran out to keep supplying it with energy.” She then added, “I apologize if that was overstepping.”

"You prioritized the ritual; why would that be overstepping?" Jake smiled.

The ritual had indeed progressed as he wanted, and with every passing day, the energy within the egg that the boulder housed in its spatially expanded interior grew stronger and stronger. Still dormant, mind you, but Jake was building up to something. He had delayed finishing the ritual and actually awakening the Bee Queen for quite a simple reason: He didn’t want a D-grade Queen.

Jake wanted to hatch a C-grade. Insect monsters—or ectognamorphs—were quite a bit different than other monster types, and Queens were even more different. They were very much a caste-based race, and Jake wanted a powerful Queen from the get-go. The chances of birthing what the books described as a true "Hive Queen" were low if done through evolution, but Jake believed it was possible to do using this ritual and some special Jake sauce.

He was not ignorant of the effect he apparently had on beasts and monsters. Sylphie and Sandy were proof of what happened when Jake interfered in the evolutionary process, even just a little. How or why he was like that, he didn’t know, but he knew it had to have something to do with his Bloodline.

Anyway, to hatch a C-grade, there were some requirements. The most important of which was the source of energy in the ritual having to be at least of that level, meaning Jake had to at least be C-grade to get the result he wanted. However, it wasn’t like he was delaying spawning a C-grade only because he had to wait for his own evolution, as the egg also needed ample time to grow.

Before the egg could even absorb C-grade energy, it needed to grow enough through the absorption of D-grade energy and Records. That was what Jake was currently doing—or had Meira doing—and it helped create a powerful foundation. Once it was saturated, Jake could introduce C-grade energy, hopefully leading to a qualitative change and making it into a C-grade egg that Jake could further mutate using Jake Records.

"Thank you, Lord Thayne." Meira still bowed, even if Jake said it was fine. Finally, she turned and looked at Scarlett. "May I know who the guest my Lord has brought along is?"

He felt like she had an odd emphasis on the word "my" but didn’t really think about it. He probably misunderstood.

"Scarlett, Meira; Meira, Scarlett," Jake quickly introduced them. "Meira works here and is a friend, and Scarlett is a friend from my home planet that helped me out quite a few times."

"Pleased to make your acquaintance," Meira said, bowing to Scarlett.

Scarlett looked between Jake and Meira before slightly bowing to Meira. "Nice to meet you, too."

Jake was happy to see them be polite to each other. Way better than the last time he’d introduced friends to each other. "Have you been doing well while I was gone?" Jake asked the elf.

"Yes, Lord Thayne,” she answered with a big smile. “I have attended lessons regularly, and the honored Grand Elder still taught me nearly daily until recently. The Grand Elder will surely also be happy to welcome you back. However, I have not seen the Grand Elder for the last week, as he has been busy assisting the Malefic One, making him leave me with self-study material."

Scarlett perked up at the mention of the Malefic One and looked at Meira again a bit weirdly.

Jake butted in to explain, "Meira is getting taught by Duskleaf, the disciple of the Viper."

He had thought that explanation would help, but no. The poor snake girl once again became nervous and bowed. "I apologize for not recognizing the Grand Disciple of the Malefic One."

"Okay, none of that. Use names, you two. Besides, if you join the Order too, I am sure Duskleaf would also give you a few tips here and there." Jake shook his head. "But first, we have to get you into the Order, of course."

"How would one undertake such an honor?" Scarlett asked with much interest.

"That…" Jake was about to answer when he stopped. He… kind of didn’t know? He had joined the Academy of the Order, but, thinking about it, had Jake ever properly joined the Order? What did it even mean to properly join the Order? He knew from Viridia’s propaganda lesson that for anyone with a Blessing, becoming a member was just a formality, so it shouldn’t be a challenge. He just wasn’t sure how it could be done.

In retrospect, maybe he should have paid more attention during the lesson…

"Do you have any talent in alchemy?" Jake asked her.

"Sadly, this one is only skilled in the cultivation of personal venoms," Scarlett admitted. There was no hint of shame or embarrassment in the statement, though. Which was good, as Jake didn’t see it as a demerit either. Being specialized was good.

Jake knew that as a member of the Order, Scarlett would also semi-join the Academy, in that she could attend lessons if she wanted. The few combat lessons there would maybe interest her. It would be a bit like Draskil, who Jake knew wasn’t really into any kind of traditional alchemy either.

As he considered how to make her join, Meira spoke up. "My Lord, any official from the Order of the Malefic Viper is capable of initiating new members into the Order, and those with sufficient rank can grant membership without further approval as long as the proper steps are undertaken."

"Oh?" Jake asked, surprised. "Have you been looking into joining the Order?"

"I… had lessons about it," she answered.

Jake frowned, as he knew from her tone that she wasn’t talking about Academy lessons, but those she’d gotten before she came to work for Jake. It did make sense, though. Jake remembered the vampire crafter who had helped him upgrade his necklace and her explanation of how she had been a slave once. It made sense that slaves were taught how to potentially stop being slaves and join, at the very least, to give them false hope.

"What do these steps entail?" Jake inquired further.

"Personal approval of a member, signage of a contract with agreed-upon terms, and an evaluation of talent," Meira dutifully explained. "Usually, a background search will also be done, along with a karmic reading. However, for those with Blessings, none of this is needed besides the contract of terms, and all the contract will entail is that membership remains active as long as the Blessing is not withdrawn or denounced. At least for lower-tier Blessings… I am not sure about the procedures for those with Greater or Divine Blessings, much less a True Blessing."

Jake nodded. Getting her to join should be easy enough, then. He was also pleasantly surprised by Meira, as getting her to talk so much tended to be damn hard, especially with her not getting nervous. She had spoken with great confidence, and Jake felt oddly proud of her.

"Thanks for the explanation, Meira." Jake smiled at her and gave her a thumbs-up.

"It… I only did as expected…" she muttered nervously.

And we’re back.

Shaking his head, Jake turned to Scarlett. "Seems like getting you in should be easy enough. Wanna get it fixed right away?"

Jake was not one to delay things, even if he had just returned.

"Yes, please!" Scarlett nodded as if she had just been asked whether she wanted a high-tier natural treasure with toxic properties.

Taking out his token, Jake felt how it was now active again after returning. The token did not work on Earth for obvious reasons, as it functioned off some grand formation somewhere in the Order, Jake reckoned. He infused energy into it and made a call to someone he hadn’t contacted in a while.

It connected, and he instantly heard her voice.

"Lord Thayne!” Irin the succubus said. “It has been quite a while since anyone heard anything from you. Is everything all right? Did you enter secluded training? Ah, sorry for blabbering; I assume you contacted me for a reason. What can I do for you?"

Being an official of the Order, she was the first one Jake thought to contact. He did also have the contact information of the Hall Master, Viridia, but it seemed a bit much to call the CEO of a company with billions of workers to help register a new employee.

"Hey, Irin. Been a while, yeah. And everything is fine; I just had to deal with some issues back on Earth. An enemy Chosen thought it was a good idea to invade the planet and raise a ruckus, so I had a civil war and an asshole Chosen to deal with before I could return. It is fixed for now, but still annoying. Anyway, the reason I contacted you was that I brought along a friend from my home planet who would like to join the Order of the Malefic Viper. She got a Blessing, so it should be possible, right?" He knew he probably didn’t need to explain everything, but it just seemed nice to tell her after he had gone AWOL.

After a brief period of silence, she responded, "That sounds… way above my paygrade. The Chosen stuff. When it comes to joining the Order, it is nothing more than a meager formality, simplified even further by her already having a Blessing. Would it be possible for me to come by?"

"Sure thing," Jake approved.

"I will be around in a few minutes. Good to hear from you again, Lord Thayne."

Jake disconnected the call and turned back to Scarlett. "I will have a friend come by in a bit to help you join," he said with a smile.

"Thank you!" Scarlett bowed once more.

Jake went over to do a quick check-up of the Bee Queen formation while he waited and made sure nothing had gone awry. As he analyzed the formation, he noticed a few spots where it felt… lacking. Jake was not sure what was wrong, but he knew there were faint flaws or at least places with room for improvement. He made mental notes to address this later, once more thanking his high Perception for allowing him to notice the problem. Without the stat growth he had experienced since he last upgraded the formation, he would not have noticed these minor elements at all.

As he was still looking things over, a new figure appeared. Jake instantly felt the familiar yet slightly foreign aura that washed out from this arrival. He looked over and saw someone he clearly recognized as Irinixis, but there were some slight differences. The horns on her head had grown slightly and now curved like that of a goat, though they were still small, and her body had some… changes. It was easy to know what had happened.

[Demon – lvl ???]

She had naturally evolved to C-grade. The evolution had not only led to growth in power, but also in certain other areas. The red dress with a low-cut front showed off these features quite nicely, and she flashed a radiant smile when she saw Jake while bowing deeply, only emphasizing her improved assets further.

Jake did not have a hard time figuring out why succubi were quite a popular race among the humanoids in the multiverse. Not gonna lie; she is fucking hot, Jake admitted. She'd also been before, but damn, had the evolution done work.

"Thank you for calling upon me, Lord Thayne," Irin greeted him. He also noticed how she threw quick glances at both Meira and Scarlett. Both glared back at her.

"Thanks for coming," Jake answered with a smile. "And congratulations on the evolution."

"I should be the one thanking you for my recent advances," Irin answered happily. "The opportunities our relationship have offered me are hard to comprehend, and even without those, the Records alone simply from knowing you allowed me smooth sailing. So, please, do call me if you ever need anything."

After getting done thanking each other, Jake finally got back on topic. "This here is Scarlett, a friend and ally from my home planet. Could you give me a hand and get her into the Order? Oh, while you’re at it… Meira, what do you say about also trying to join the Order?"

Meira seemed taken aback. "I believe that is premature, Lord Thayne…"

Jake frowned a bit, not sure why it would be, but still shrugged. No rush. "Okay, just Scarlett, then."

"It shall be done swiftly," Irin said as she greeted Scarlett. "My name is Irinixis; I am from the Humanoid Resources Department in the Order of the Malefic Viper. The Chosen referring you to join alone makes all of this simply a formality, but I would still offer you to go through the usual evaluation if you so desire."

"Oh, a dungeon again?" Jake asked curiously.

"Indeed," Irin confirmed.

"Should definitely go for it.”

"Then I shall take part in this evaluation," Scarlett said, nodding.

Irin smiled at Scarlett as Jake considered aloud, "Should I also go for reevaluation at some point? Maybe at C-grade?"

"If you desire to, Lord Thayne,” Irin explained. “However, realistically it will be done for nothing more than vanity, as all the additional bonuses awarded from a better token are meaningless to you. Getting a dark green token would only result in more attention being placed on you.”

"Maybe I shouldn’t, then," Jake muttered.

The demoness smiled and turned to Scarlett again. "Do you wish to begin right away or delay?"

"I wish to join as soon as possible!" Scarlett nodded enthusiastically.

"Then let’s go."

With that, Jake sent Scarlett and Irin off right away, Irin making sure to give a low bow to show off before leaving. Meira watched as they left and threw Jake a few questioning gazes without saying anything. Jake decided to just initiate the conversation himself.

"Let’s head inside, and you can give me the low-down on what has happened around here recently," Jake said to Meira.

"Yes!" the elf agreed as the two of them headed inside.

As it turned out, not much had happened—at least, not on a large scale. The entire thing with Ell’Hakan and Yip was clearly not knowledge spread openly, as it likely was—as Irin said—above their paygrade. Jake instead mostly heard about how much Meira had been studying and how she was still hanging out with that other elf, Izil. The elf and human then shifted into alchemy talks, and Jake had to admit…

It did feel good to be back in such a low-stress environment. Not for too long, though. As in, only for a bit. Jake prepared to get started immediately with his checklist right away once he had caught up with Meira, and for the next two parts, Jake had a feeling he would need to consult his dear Patron god.

Chapter 75

Not That Dense... Okay, a Little

After the Chosen’s disappearance, Irinixis had wondered what had happened for a while. She’d had no way of contracting him, as his token was unreachable, meaning he’d either been dead or not in the Order. She’d reckoned the latter for obvious reasons.

Her new teacher, the Velvet Mistress, had also agreed that nothing would have happened to him. Geniuses did not die that easily, and if he had been gone, people would have learned about it. Irin also knew that the many statues of the Viper spread around the Order would reflect the loss of a Chosen through their aura, proving that he should be fine. Or that the Viper was capable of shrugging off the loss of a Chosen without much care.

Irin had naturally hoped the Chosen was fine, as he was her golden ticket. She had gotten a new mistress at the peak of S-grade, her status elevated above anything she could ever imagine, and her evolution had even come earlier than she had expected. Irin had always believed she would be able to reach C-grade, even if she didn’t always vocalize it. However, she’d had fears of how she would make it to C-grade. D-grade was already the end of the line for most, and while C-grade was expected of her due to her heritage and position, no one expected her to ever reach B-grade. Irin hadn’t expected to ever get a shot at it either. Yet now… now it didn’t seem impossible.

All she had to do was stay in his good graces and, if possible, get even more involved with him, no matter what kind of role she was asked to perform. It was premature, but her ultimate goal was to become his personal liaison between the Order and him. To be someone officially involved and linked to the Chosen and his matters. But it was hard to get an "in," so for now, she could only try to deepen their personal relationship. One thing she had learned was that the Chosen cared little for decorum or tradition, preferring casual interactions and demeanors.

Her mistress had made her work on being more appealing to the Chosen, which included unlearning many of her old methods. The Chosen did not seem to enjoy the overly subservient types, wanting someone who treated him far more equally than someone of his status was entitled to. Not too much, though, as Irin still wanted to make it clear she was there to make his life easier while hopefully also being a friendly face.

Anyway, she had worked on this for a long time but had worried, as he had not called for her even once. Fortunately, the silence was broken when her token vibrated and she felt the signature. Elated, she greeted him, and to make it better, he even asked for assistance. Even allowed her to make a personal visit.

She had quickly gone to put on some more fitting clothes and get herself ready. The evolution to C-grade had done her many favors, if she said so herself, even if the shape of the horns could get a bit annoying and her hair got tangled during showers.

Teleporting to the residence of the Chosen, she was instantly met by two auras surpassing her own. One was from the Chosen, whom she knew she stood no chance against, even with her evolution. The second one was a female beast—a snake of some kind, from the looks of it—who had taken human form. Irin also felt the Blessing from the girl and would naturally show the due respect such a thing dictated. Helping her was part of her job and something she would happily do.

However, what she cared most about was the gaze of the Chosen. It lingered for longer than it had to, making Irin very pleased. Still, she had a job to do and showed professionalism despite the gazes of the two other women, which were certainly less friendly than the Chosen’s. One gaze was from Meira, the assigned slave for Lord Thayne. Irin was a bit surprised he asked if she wanted to join the Order too, indicating he wanted to release her. On-brand, based on what Irin had learned of Lord Thayne. If he wanted people to treat him as an equal, the thought of having a slave forced upon him must have been less than ideal. Irin had also learned about Earth from the human called Reika and come to understand a bit of their planet’s history—including how slavery was not popular in their part of the world. Downright hated, even.

The other gaze was naturally from the snake woman. A piercing one, Irin had to admit. Luckily, she saw neither of them as threats to her goals, even if they were on good terms with Lord Thayne. She also got a feeling that her goals and the goals of the slave elf were somewhat similar, if very different in approach. Both of them wanted to stay integrated with the Chosen, one way or another, to secure their own futures.

With the two girls evaluated, Irin answered some questions and led the prospective member, Scarlett, away. A bow towards the Chosen was only proper, and once more, his gaze lingered for a moment before Irin and the snake girl left. Irin, of course, knew what she was doing.

Was she what humans would call a gold-digger? Yes, though the term in the multiverse tended to refer to parasites who forcefully tried to associate themselves with powerful individuals and feed off their Records. She wasn’t ashamed of it either.

Lord Thayne wasn’t stupid and most certainly not unperceptive. He knew what she was doing and allowed it. If the parasite and target both enjoyed and found benefits in the relationship, it could only be called synergistic, couldn’t it?

Finally alone, Jake could relax. Meira had gone off to her own residence to tend to her studies after their lengthy talk, and with Scarlett and Irin also gone, Jake had the main mansion all to himself. Free of the "drama" he had just been a part of, he felt relieved. Jake was a bit dense, sure… but even he could see that the three women were interested in him. Or at least interested in his status.

However, it was honestly easiest to just act like he didn’t know. Things were just too complicated. Meira was still his slave, making it break at least a few moral lines to respond to her feelings, and Jake wasn’t even sure she actually liked him, even though she thought she did. He had helped her, and she clearly felt indebted to him. Confusing gratitude with stronger emotions was not uncommon at all.

Scarlett was just… no. She reminded Jake of a teenage girl, and she also revered Jake to an unhealthy level. With both her and Meira, the power imbalance in their relationships was all out of whack too. So… yeah, better to just ignore it.

Then there was Irin. That one felt the most complicated to Jake. So complicated he didn’t want to think too much about it, and thus proceeded to working on his checklist.

Jake had two goals for now. Sagacity of the Malefic Viper and the entire situation with sim-Jake and their joint attempt to create a skill. For both of these, Jake had some issues he needed to overcome. After some consideration, he ultimately decided to take on Sagacity first, as he wanted to fully dedicate his attention to the potential mythical skill. Also, the extra Wisdom would be nice.

With no need to delay, he got to work and sat on the sofa in the living room. There, he leaned back and stared at the ceiling while gathering his thoughts.

He already had some insights into the topic of Sagacity, especially after the last vision. For a long time, Jake had wondered what the point of the Sagacity skill even truly was. For a good reason, too.

[Sagacity of the Malefic Viper (Ancient)] – To hold just a fragment of the Wisdom of a Primordial is more than most ever achieve. Much less to be personally taught that knowledge directly by the god himself. Allows the alchemist to peek into a fragment of the Malefic Viper’s Records to seek his knowledge. Grants the alchemist of the Malefic Viper a far better understanding of mana and of most affinities. Allows the Alchemist to make creations he does not have the associated crafting skill for. (Does not receive stat effectiveness bonuses without associated skill). Passively provides 1 Wisdom per level in Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your search for knowledge be as inexhaustible as the Malefic One.

Sure, it did help Jake in some ways, but it was minimal. It had two primary passive elements: a better understanding of mana and the ability to craft without associated crafting skills. The first part had some value, but it was just a small passive bonus that he barely noticed.

Then there was the thing about not needing a crafting skill. It sounded nice, but… Jake had these crafting skills. He had all he needed, and his evolutions tended to just give the skills, whether he wanted them or not. Also, if Jake could choose, he would want the crafting skill anyway for the stat effectiveness bonus that Sagacity did not offer.

To summarize, Jake only really got anything out of the extra Wisdom and the mana thing. Which seemed really subpar compared to all his other Malefic Viper Legacy skills.

Okay, there was one final active part of the skill: peering into the Record Fragment of the Viper. This part had been pretty useful, but… Jake couldn’t see why he needed a skill for that. He had stolen the drop of blood without a skill, hadn’t he? And he’d also restrained it within his Soulspace quite easily.

Overall, Jake found little value in the Sagacity skill and even wondered what its primary function was and why the Viper had it, as the blood-peering part was clearly not a part of the Viper’s version. At least, Jake had wondered this until the latest vision. He had kind of misunderstood the core of Sagacity from the beginning, not realizing that the reality was… the skill wasn’t made for the enlightened races. It was made for monsters.

Jake had seen the Viper try and craft without the required crafting skill, noting how difficult it was. It was, without exaggerating, a hundred times harder than crafting with a skill. The Viper had struggled to make health potions even after he found the issue, and that was while in C-grade. Jake could only imagine the pain of having to do this entire process of figuring out a "manual" approach to every new alchemical method. But Jake had a feeling the Viper had done exactly this and then condensed it into this one skill. A skill that was now part of his Legacy and could be obtained or taught to other monsters, allowing them to benefit from his trial and error.

It was a catch-all skill for alchemy crafting. A way for monsters to still be alchemists and compete on a far more equal playing field with the enlightened races. The things about affinities and mana were just passive elements gained from a better understanding of the fundamental principles of how alchemy worked. Or, perhaps, an added bonus, as the system knew the significantly reduced value the Sagacity skill had for someone like Jake.

He felt like he was on the right track, but some things still bothered him… and while he tended to prefer to avoid it, he decided to approach the source of the skill itself to confirm his theory.

"Hey, Villy…"

"Yeah?" a voice answered as a smirking god stared straight down at Jake’s face, obstructing his vision of the nice ceiling.

"I thought you were busy?" Jake said without moving.

"I am. That is why you are talking to this avatar and not the real me." Villy jumped over the back of the couch and sat on it. "Can you tell the difference?"

Jake stared at the so-called avatar for a moment and tried to find any indications of it not being the real thing. The aura was vast and powerful as usual, but in its muted state, Jake had a hard time getting a read on it. "No, not really," he admitted.

"No need to be embarrassed—you weren’t meant to, and this avatar can exert a good ten percent of my full power if push comes to shove. But this is not why you asked for me. What seems to trouble my little Chosen this time around? Oh, if it is love advice, then sure, you have fun with the succubus. You are both consenting adults. Plus, she seems like a fun one, and—"

"I wanted to ask about something with the First Sage," Jake interrupted loudly.

Villy shut up but still smirked. "He didn’t strike me as your type, so not love advice, I see. What do you want to know?"

"It is actually more about Sagacity than it is about him, but I have a feeling they are related. Firstly, the name Sagacity was not chosen randomly or decided by the system, was it?"

After a few moments of thinking, the Viper sighed. "No, it was not. As you probably already guessed, the skill is named after the First Sage. Tell me, what else have you concluded about this peculiar little skill?"

"It was made as a way to allow monsters to do alchemy without the crafting skills by creating one that does it all. It relies on your experiences and what you learned to fill in the gaps left by not having the many alchemical crafting skills.”

"Partly accurate. Yes, it is good for monsters and primarily used by them. Shit, Sagacity is one of the main reasons why monsters who specialize in alchemy prefer the Order over other places like the Altmar Empire, and Sagacity is one of the few Legacy skills that can be taught; the Records are easily obtained to get the skill during a skill selection. But you missed that certain enlightened races with only a profession or a class can make great use of it. Plus, it is a skill tied to my Legacy and not necessarily to the alchemy profession, meaning even those with a profession utterly unrelated to alchemy can get it and become part-time alchemists.”

"Was it your or the First Sage’s idea to make this kind of all-encompassing skill?" Jake asked. He still felt a bit bad for not telling Villy about what he had felt at the end of the last vision, where the First Sage had clearly been aware of him before the Viper knew. Which made Jake wonder if what the Viper had done—learned to craft without a crafting skill—was one of the reasons the First Sage had wanted to take him in.

"Hm, a bit of both," Villy answered. "He did tell me one of the reasons he wanted to teach me was to also learn from me. He was interested in all sorts of ways one could perform magic without any skill or system assistance, as well as how one could make use of the peculiarities of the system. His teachings were part of the reason I advised you to practice mana the first time we met."

The Viper smiled a bit to himself. "The old man used to have a saying about how experiences gained by he who knows nothing are infinitely more valuable than he who follows a false truth, as the true essence of reality can only be found by an unspoiled mind. In other words, the potential truths one can learn alone without guidance are worth far more than those merely taught. Think of your arcane affinity. If I had told you about how to find an arcane affinity and how you could try and create one, I doubt it would have ever manifested. In some ways, your ignorance led to it appearing, as its very nature is rooted in your basic understanding of mana."

"I do remember you mentioning something like that before," Jake said, nodding. "But Sagacity strikes me more as a skill that is heavily tied to prior experiences and not new discoveries."

"True, true. Partly. Sagacity is, as you said, the result of a combined effort of the First Sage and me to make a methodology for those who cannot gain the alchemy profession. At least, that was the initial core of the skill, but it has, from there, expanded. The core now revolves around my experience and knowledge more than simply crafting methods. Your version also has some elements related to mana, and you got a drop of blood that contains Records, right? Those are now also tied to it. So, to sum it up for ya, Sagacity is knowledge incarnate."

Jake opened his mouth to ask something, but he instantly forgot it when a lightbulb went off. "I… think I have an idea of what to do…"

"Then my job here is done," Villy said, smiling.

"May need you for something else if you are up for it later," Jake said.

"Then I guess we will see each other again soon," the Viper answered as he popped out of existence.

Jake didn’t delay, instantly getting himself comfortable and entering meditation. Once more, Jake felt like he had missed something very obvious…

Chapter 76

The Library of a Sage

Alone again, Jake had time to think. As Villy had said, then the core of Sagacity was knowledge, also reflected by it granting Wisdom. Yet Jake had not really received any instinctual knowledge when he got the skill about anything related to alchemy. It had added knowledge through the drop of blood, but Jake didn’t count that, as it was just another potential source. The knowledge of mana affinities did kind of count, but that was more just another way to identify things… which led to Jake’s realization.

Jake had learned a lot since he became an alchemist, especially in recent times after joining the Order. He had gone through so many damn books, studied the drop of blood quite a bit, and eaten like a madman for Palate. Yet even if he had done all of this, he had not been given a single upgrade to the two skills he had that dealt with alchemical knowledge: Herbology and Toxicology.

[Herbology (Common)] – Grants knowledge of herbs found throughout the multiverse. The most numerous source of natural treasures comes in the form of herbs found throughout existence. The knowledge of plants and their effects is, therefore, essential to any alchemist. An alchemist must know what he works with in order to create his products, after all. Grants the ability to recognize herbs at a glance and correctly Identify their properties.

[Toxicology (Uncommon)] – The knowledge of all that is toxic. Be able to recognize poisonous substances at a glance and correctly Identify their properties. To concoct the deadliest toxins, one must know what to mix, after all.

Jake had had these skills since the very beginning of his journey as an alchemist, neither of them upgrading or even showing signs of getting upgraded. Not getting one upgraded in E-grade was kind of understandable, but how could he not have upgraded one of them at D-grade? Especially Herbology, which was stuck at common rarity? Toxicology, too, should have at least shown some signs of upgrading. That, or Jake should have at least had an idea of how to improve them.

Now, Jake realized that these two would never upgrade. Not because Jake sucked so bad at learning things about toxic materials or herbs, but because the Records required to upgrade the skills went somewhere else: Sagacity of the Malefic Viper.

The Legacy of the Malefic Viper was a complete system for alchemy. With those nine skills alone, a monster or even a member of the enlightened races could become an exceptional alchemist in no way inferior to more traditional ones. At least, not when it came to poisons. To achieve this, the usual skills alchemists got from their profession had to also exist in some shape or form within the Legacy, including the knowledge-related skills that allowed him to know what he was looking at. Would it not only make sense for Sagacity to be where this knowledge was focused?

In fact, wasn’t this logic also true with other passive skills or even active skills Jake had? Cultivate Toxin was already heavily related to Palate of the Malefic Viper, and Jake could also see Touch being related to Alchemist’s Purification… Maybe even the Alchemical Flame, though Jake had a suspicion that one was a bit different. Stuff for later. Focus on Sagacity now.

Jake believed that Toxicology and Herbology had both become obsolete, yet they still remained skills. Which led him to the most obvious conclusion: have Sagacity absorb them. He had tried two skills seemingly unrelated to the Malefic Viper’s influence and even formed a Malefic Viper skill before, so he knew it was possible. One had to remember that Sense of the Malefic Viper had come from the merging of Sense Herb and Sense Poison all the way back in G-grade. However, back then, it had happened by itself, making Jake think there was more to upgrading Sagacity than merely merging the skills. Or maybe he didn’t know how to merge them?

As he kept considering the skill, he went in the direction of what Sagacity was linked to. Sagacity was a bit like the focal point of all knowledge his other skills gave him. It was fed by Palate and Sense all the time. All he learned went into the Records of Sagacity, but also things he didn’t know went into it. That was when another light bulb went off.

Back when Herbology and Toxicology had been gained, another skill had been affected. A skill that was even mentioned in both their descriptions: Identify. Jake slapped his knee and grinned as he activated his Path of the Heretic-Chosen skill. He hadn’t been sure, but the system thought he had considered the skill enough to be granted a vision.

Do you wish to experience the Legacy of the Malefic Viper? Uses remaining: 1

It was the final use, and Jake smiled to himself as he was whisked away.

"The system is limitless in possibilities," the old man said with a smile. “Even an immortal could spend an infinite lifetime to try and learn everything, yet after countless years, the immortal would only come to learn that he has not progressed at all. For as he learns, new knowledge appears. This very same folly is what you are pursuing right now.”

In front of him sat the Malefic Viper, deep in thought as he considered the words. Jake had appeared as usual, and predictably, he had popped in with the First Sage present. Jake was sure by now that the system wanted him to keep seeing this old man… That, or he’d had so much influence on Villy’s formative years that seeing him was unavoidable.

"So you are saying I need to change course?" Villy asked with a deep frown.

"You misunderstand, for omniscience does exist; it is merely reserved for the system itself,” the First Sage replied. “It knows all, and sometimes the key is not to learn everything yourself, but to find a way to make the system give you the knowledge you require. To prove yourself worthy and entitled to the knowledge you demand. Your approach so far has been good, but it is not sustainable. You seek to learn of all herbs or toxins yourself, developing general skills based on your experiences, but as you progress, you will come to learn how unfeasible this is.”

Once more, the Viper was deep in thought. After a bit, he voiced his considerations. "I do see the problem… Trying to design a method for every kind of potential product and with every single combination of ingredients is impossible. Just learning enough about different ingredients is utterly unfeasible…"

Jake nodded along, as he knew the direction in which this was going. He saw on the face of the First Sage that he was also hoping for the Viper to realize what he meant. It felt good to have it figured out before the snake god. Second time in a row, too.

The Viper asked a few more minor questions as he slowly understood. With realization, his eyes opened wide. "Will the system allow such a thing? No… will it actively help to do something like that?"

"Never has the system demanded perfection, only adequate proof that you are qualified. Invisible thresholds are in place for us to discover, and all it requires of you is to pass this threshold, and it shall assist you.”

As for what they were talking about? Well, system assistance—or, more accurately, to have the skill recognized as what the Viper wanted it to be. He had hit the nail on its head already: Manually improving everything was simply impossible.

When Jake used Brew Potion, the system assistance from the skill always did the same thing—at least, if one focused on the outcome. However, in reality, its effects varied for each individual craft. No two ingredients were one hundred percent identical. Sometimes it took a millisecond more to heat something, or perhaps a single more point of mana was injected. All of this led to variation, and with each variation, the minor corrections from system assistance varied in turn.

This is to say that if Villy wanted to make Sagacity based solely on his own experiences, then it would never work, as he naturally couldn’t have an experience identical to anyone else. No, what Sagacity—his current version, too—did was adopt the functionality of the usual system assistance. Because the system obviously knew exactly what corrections had to be made.

As for how the Viper had realized this goal... Well, Jake guessed it still had to do with a shitload of trial and error and learning how to craft a myriad of different things manually. Then, at some point, he had passed a threshold, as the First Sage said, and the gaps had been filled in.

Of course, none of this related to the upgrade Jake wanted. This was just Jake finally understanding how his current version worked. However, realizing how it worked with the crafting skills allowed Jake to understand that the same concept applied to the alchemical knowledge skills.

Almost as if the old man had known of Jake’s thoughts, he continued, "The same is true when it comes to the knowledge of what. Learning the how of crafting only matters after you know what you can craft with and become able to recognize potential. Right now, you use ingredients you have consumed countless samples of, or at most variants. You know them, but what about when you encounter something new? You eat it, I would reckon, but is that truly the best approach to learning even just the basics?"

Jake barely had to listen anymore, as he already knew what he wanted to do and what direction he wanted to take the skill. He had not even reached the crucial part of the vision yet, where he merged with the Viper, but had already begun his own process of upgrading the skill.

Merging Herbology and Toxicology into Sagacity was a given. Keeping the crafting skills separate had a purpose, at least for now, so he had no interest in merging those, but the knowledge-related skills had no extra bonus. They just passively gave knowledge that he could access through Identify.

So, if he combined the two, it only made sense for Identify to also pull from Sagacity. It perhaps already did; Jake had no way of being sure. He reckoned it did pull from Sagacity, as he guessed one of the reasons he’d even gotten the skill selection option was because of the Trial of Myriad Poisons, which gave him a lot of knowledge through Palate. An event that should, in retrospect, have resulted in at least Herbology evolving.

But… Jake was not satisfied with merely pulling on Sagacity when he used Identify. The First Sage talked about pulling knowledge directly from the system. The Sagacity skill already did this in his usual form, but Jake did not have the usual form. He had a bastardized version tied to a drop of blood from the Viper. A drop of blood that Jake controlled inside his Soulspace. So, why couldn’t Jake pull on this drop too? Link himself more with it and extract knowledge in a fashion similar to what the old Herbology and Toxicology did?

Jake split his attention between his own internal thoughts and plans and the conversation between the Viper and the First Sage. The old man spoke more words of wisdom while the Viper worked on properly creating the Sagacity skill for perhaps the very first time. It likely hadn’t been called Sagacity back then, but Jake knew it was a massive undertaking nevertheless.

It was creating a framework. An entire methodology separate from traditional alchemy, all boiled into a single skill. Some corners had to be cut—such as the lack of stat effectiveness bonuses—and several other minor things here and there. This first version would be a far cry from what Sagacity was during the 93rd Era, but it was a monumental feat for a C-grade.

Such a monumental feat that the Viper obviously struggled. He had a hard time getting it all together and creating a framework capable of facilitating such a massive undertaking. He had clearly worked on it a lot, but even as the time in the vision sped up, he lacked progress. Days turned to weeks, weeks to months, and months to years. The Viper was unmoving for more than a decade, and yet the First Sage never left his side. He remained there to answer any questions the Viper had, even if months passed between the Viper exiting meditation.

Yet even after this long, the Viper was not done. Frustration began to appear on the future Primordial’s face. "I… It’s difficult," he said, shaking his head. "There are too many elements, too much to slot into place…"

"Visualize it," the First Sage said. "A metaphor is there to ease understanding. Simplify elements into a concept you do understand. What does your skill look like in your mind?"

"I…" The Viper frowned, not saying more. It was obvious he wasn’t sure where to go or what to do.

The First Sage sighed. "Once. Once I can assist you."

The Viper perked up. "Really, Master?"

"Yes. But only this once.” The old man nodded as he stood up. He went over to the Viper and knelt in front of the cross-legged snake in human form. He smiled at his disciple, who began to look a bit conflicted. Worried, even. "I already promised. Now, allow yourself to indulge in creation. Open your mind."

The First Sage raised a hand… and Jake felt like the world twisted.

He felt something he had only ever felt once before. Like the bounds of reality shifted to allow the impossible through sheer will and enlightenment. The hand gave off an aura that pressured him on a fundamental level, accelerating his heartbeat. There was not a shred of doubt in his mind…

A Transcendence.

Jake had no idea what it did… but he knew he was about to find out. This had to be the most important part of the vision, and the system also clearly agreed, as Jake felt himself merge fully with the Viper the second before the old man laid his palm on the head of the Viper.

A cool sensation spread throughout the Viper’s—and thus Jake’s—body. His mind felt clearer than ever before. Then everything changed. The walls of the room they were in disintegrated, revealing a world of nothingness beyond. A perfect white void, reminiscent of the spaces the system had conjured at times.

"Everything needs a foundation," the voice of the First Sage echoed. “Allow your mind to form the Origin.” He was nowhere to be found, and yet it felt like he was everywhere.

The Viper focused as a massive disc of stone appeared below his feet, more than fifty meters in diameter. Jake sensed that Villy somehow knew what to do, despite not being entirely sure why he knew.

"Visualize your desires. What do you want—nay, demand—of the skill? Breathe in, and with your exhale, may your reality materialize."

Villy inhaled some unknown particles. In the next second, he breathed out, and a storm of colored wisps exited his mouth. They swirled as a wood-like structure appeared on the edges of the disc in all directions, as if the Viper was building a tower around himself.

The wood-like structure began to morph further as it divided all over. It took Jake a moment before he realized what was being made. They were bookshelves.

These shelves shot upwards into the white sky, expanding beyond Jake’s realm of perception within a mere second… and they just seemed to keep going. Then, from the bottom, books began to appear. All of them had the exact same blank, black cover, but each gave off a slightly different sensation.

A hundred, a thousand, a million, a billion… The books kept multiplying infinitely into the sky, though at some point, they stopped giving him any sensations. He knew it was because they had no content… no Records.

"A library of a sage," the First Sage spoke, narrating what the Viper made. “Its contents are not infinite, but it contains infinite space for expansion. The system allowed the role of the scribe, as the blank books are filled with insight upon your demand. You, the sole librarian. With time, omniscience the goal.

"An ambitious desire. Can you truly realize it?"

The old man appeared in front of Jake and Villy. He held out his hand with the palm up, and the Viper reached out. Villy held his own hand in front of the palm of the Sage as he gritted his teeth. Blood began to flow from his eyes, ears, and nose, and a bloody mist seeped out of his body. There was something off with the blood, though.

This entire place was not real—or at least, it wasn’t directly linked to the outside world. The blood seeping out represented something different from physical damage. A sacrifice. An offering. It took Jake a moment to understand, but soon enough, he knew what it was. It was the Records of another skill. Villy was upgrading it, or maybe sacrificing it to get what would eventually become Sagacity.

Jake watched on intently as the blood pooled together and formed a single drop. Then, in the very next moment, the entire library tower that Villy had created began to turn red and melt into blood. The blood pooled together towards the center of the platform they stood on before rising up and merging with the droplet. Finally, even the platform turned into blood and merged with the droplet.

"An offering made, a framework created, an Origin formed… Now claim it," the First Sage said as his own body faded away.

The drop of blood floated forward and entered the forehead of the Viper. The moment it entered his body, the white void around them shattered like it had been made of glass. As the world itself fell apart, Jake tried to understand everything that had happened. He had so many questions, and he hoped to maybe figure out what the hell the First Sage had actually done.

Villy’s body disappeared, disconnecting Jake from him and leaving him to float alone, ready for time to rewind again. He really wanted to once more experience the—

The collapsing world froze. It was as if time itself had stopped, and Jake felt a stream of attention focus on him. In the next moment, the First Sage appeared right in front of Jake and stared straight at him.

"Records not of this time. An Origin that—"

And then Jake was back in his living room.

Chapter 77

Profession = Done

Jake just sat and stared into the wall for a good few seconds, wondering what the actual fuck had just happened. It was as if the vision had been interrupted somehow, or maybe forcefully ended. Or maybe it was always meant to end in this fashion? Though that would also be incredibly odd.

The skill had allowed Jake to do something he thought was impossible. He had experienced a Transcendence, a skill that should be outside the system. Based on what Jake knew, a normal skill like his Path of the Heretic-Chosen should not have allowed this, in the same way that no skill would allow someone to hide from Jake’s Bloodline-made Sphere of Perception.

Yet it had. Maybe it was because Jake experienced Records of the past as they were? Though this experience did make him wonder if it truly was like that. Jake remembered how it had felt like Valdemar had, in some vague way, been aware of him. Meanwhile, this time, the First Sage had one hundred percent been aware.

Did this mean that all the way back in the First Era, these two had actually seen him? If that was the case, didn’t it kind of play into the whole theory of predetermination, as it would mean that the system had known, all the way back in the First Era, that Jake could be born in the 93rd Era and then get a skill to view these Record Fragments?

Or maybe it created a new kind of reality if they noticed, a bit like the simulated world sim-Jake came from… It was hard to tell.

Then there was the entire Transcendence itself. Villy had said the First Sage had several, and this was Jake’s first time seeing one. What it actually did, Jake had no idea, but he reckoned it had something to do with skill creation or modification somehow. If that was the case, it was a damn strong one, especially as it could be used on other people, though it did make Jake question the repercussions of using such a skill. The First Sage had clearly wanted to avoid using it and had said he would only help once, indicating there was a good reason to not overuse this Transcendence.

Though Jake could not argue with the result. Even now, Jake remembered the feelings he’d shared with the Viper. The sheer level of comprehension. He’d felt like every book was at his fingertips, his mind clearer than ever, and only his desire to create the skill had mattered. To call it enlightenment was not quite accurate, as it had felt… different. Like it was more than that.

Jake shook his head as he tried to focus on what he could control and what mattered. Upgrading his Sagacity. While this vision had been the weirdest one he had ever experienced by quite a margin, it had done its job quite efficiently.

Visualizing a skill was not anything new to Jake. He was pretty good at visualizing things. His Soulspace was proof of that, with a massive, cursed chimera monster roaming about. Jake was a very visual person by nature—something his insane Perception should maybe have indicated. Seeing the library that the First Sage had had Villy build made Jake understand far better what Sagacity truly was.

And allowed him to upgrade his own version.

Jake sat down in meditation and got to work on properly condensing all he had learned and all he wanted into the skill. He’d felt right at the cusp even before the vision and was now more sure than ever. In fact, he felt a bit bolder than before.

It still ended up taking nearly a full day for Jake to get what he wanted, but he got it in the end.

[Sagacity of the Malefic Viper (Ancient --> Legendary)] – Blood containing Records, personal teachings, insights from a sage, and the knowledge of a traditional alchemist. Combined, you bring honor to your Patron as you strive for omniscience. Allows the alchemist to extract knowledge from a fragment of the Malefic Viper’s Records to claim his knowledge as your own. Grants the Alchemist of the Malefic Viper a far better understanding of mana and of most affinities. Grants the alchemist knowledge of a myriad of alchemical ingredients, allowing him to far more easily Identify them. Allows the alchemist to make creations he does not have the associated crafting skill for. (Does not receive stat effectiveness bonuses without associated skill). Passively provides 3 Wisdom per level in Alchemist of the Malefic Viper. May your search for knowledge be as inexhaustible as the Malefic One.

Jake felt like an influx of knowledge slammed into his head the moment everything fell into place. It was like a library—akin to the one Villy had constructed—appeared in his head, reorganizing itself to be more systematic and usable. Almost as if all of Jake’s prior alchemical knowledge had come from a massive pile of books that had now all been sorted and categorized.

This knowledge was also far more than what he’d had before. One had to remember that Jake only really had knowledge of herbs and toxic materials, with the Identify skill also being restricted to these two categories of alchemical ingredients. What would have been the geology, metallurgy, and several more skills were part of Sagacity now.

It was all sorted into this metaphorical library, the books ready to be pulled out whenever Identify found something it corresponded to. It was not like Jake suddenly knew a shitload more about rocks, just that he could now at least pull out the knowledge.

This part of the upgrade was great, even if it was more wide than deep, with Jake not immediately seeing much value from his newfound abilities. He couldn’t exactly use rocks and metal for much with his usual alchemy methods, after all.

However, it did not end there. Herbology and Toxicology were now gone, but both had been intrinsically tied to another skill of his that now also showed signs of evolving.

Identify was a skill that had last evolved when Jake got his profession and thus the Herbology and Toxicology skills. It had not shown signs of upgrading since, which Jake partly recognized was his fault for never truly trying. Now that it showed signs anyway… Jake dove in, still sensing his mind’s focus and clarity from the Sagacity upgrade.

The skill did one thing and one thing only: It allowed Jake to peer into the Records of an entity. It could be protected against, but Jake had found ways to circumvent this protection before using his high Perception, so that was the first thing he thought about. Secondly, Jake had spent over a decade practicing how to sense and thus veil his own Blessing. It made no sense for him to not leverage this.

He thought it would have been harder to upgrade the skill… but surprisingly enough, it took little effort as long as he put his mind to it.

[Identify (Common)] - Identification skill, known by all but the smallest of children of the myriad races. The skill allows you to attempt to identify any object or creature you are focusing on.

-->

[Identify (Rare)] – An improved version of the standard Identification skill, a skill known by all but the smallest of children of the myriad races. The skill allows you to attempt to identify any object or creature you are focusing on. Allows for the detection of Blessings. The Identity level limit and effectiveness is based on Perception. Cannot Identify any creature above your own grade.

The skill had gone up not just one, but two entire rarities. The added effects were as expected, and honestly, Jake didn’t feel anything different about the skill now compared to before. Given the limitation of still being unable to Identify anyone above his grade, it wasn’t like being able to see a potentially higher level cap mattered either. Though, hopefully, it would be useful in C-grade. The effectiveness part linked to Perception was definitely the biggest bonus, as that could probably allow him to pierce a lot of veils people made to hide their levels. Finally, being able to see if people got Blessings was a nice addition.

Jake had also made it so that he pulled on the drop of blood that contained Records of the Viper quite a bit for the Blessing-detection part. Jake knew how to detect if someone had a Blessing but was clueless as to which god had given the Blessing—unless it was from someone he recognized. So he definitely needed system assistance for that part.

Leaning back on the sofa, Jake took a deep breath, satisfied with his results. Upgrading Identify had not been on his to-do list, but doing it was definitely a welcome addition. He had even gotten some ideas as to how other alchemy skills could maybe be merged with the Viper’s Legacy skills with time, but that was not something he would pursue. No, for now, he was more than happy.

All nine Legacy skills at legendary.

That had to be considered quite the feat, right? Jake at least assumed it would have a positive influence on his upcoming evolution. He knew that his profession was unique, so anything he did now could result in a better version that gave more stats or maybe better skills when the time came. At least, that was his working theory.

Smiling to himself, Jake checked off the last thing that had to do with his profession before the evolution. Jake decided to pull up all his profession skills to check if he had missed something or had an obvious one he could try to upgrade.

Profession Skills: [Path of the Heretic-Chosen (Unique)], [Brew Potion (Common)], [Alchemist’s Purification (Common)], [Alchemical Flame (Uncommon)], [Craft Elixir (Uncommon)], [Cultivate Toxin (Uncommon)], [Concoct Poison (Rare)], [Malefic Viper’s Poison (Epic)], [Soul Ritualism of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist (Ancient)], [Advanced Core Manipulation (Ancient)], [Blood of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Sagacity of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Sense of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Wings of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Legacy Teachings of the Heretic-Chosen Alchemist (Legendary)], [Palate of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Pride of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Scales of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Fangs of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)], [Anomalous Soul of the Heretic-Chosen (Legendary)]

--

There were some skills of low rarity. Purification and Cultivate Toxin were two obvious ones. However, Jake firmly believed upgrading either of these wouldn’t matter much for his evolution, especially given that Jake now believed Cultivate Toxin would one day become one with the Legacy skills.

Jake concluded that he was indeed done with his profession for the rest of D-grade. Now, it was time for his class and the goal of creating a skill of a higher rarity than he had ever done before.

He and sim-Jake had considered this skill a lot and quickly come to realize that they were indeed arrogant idiots who thought creating a mythical skill was far easier than it actually was. However, more than arrogant idiots, they were stubborn idiots who would keep working on it until it worked. But to stand any chance of creating the skill, they needed time.

Well, they needed time to not pass as fast as it tended to. If not, then Jake could see himself missing a certain Prima Guardian coming to Earth, all his friends reaching C-grade and getting well into it, and not seeing his family for too long… Shit, maybe there would be a bunch of other timed system events he would miss. Also, going missing for a bloody long time could lead to unexpected issues, especially with bastards like Ell’Hakan still around.

Besides, all Jake would need to do was sit on his ass and meditate.

Jake closed his eyes for a moment and entered his Soulspace. Sim-Jake gave him a nod, affirming that he was ready.

Now the only problem was figuring out how to have time pass a little differently to not miss stuff…

"Vil—"

"Hey again," the snake god said as he popped up right behind the couch once more, even faster than last time. "This time, I am interested in knowing what the vision showed you as it relates to Sagacity. What did you see?"

Jake was a bit surprised at the Viper seeming to actually care so much. He decided not to hide anything as he told him what he had experienced from start to end—including the First Sage recognizing him.

After Jake was done talking, the Viper sat in an armchair across from Jake with a hand on his chin, thinking. "Very… interesting,” he finally said, “but not unsurprising. It is a unique skill, so perhaps it makes sense that you can experience a Transcendence, though it does sound like you didn’t truly feel its effects. I can promise you that what you went through is nothing compared to me. First of all, for me, it felt like I was in that other world for... I would say about fourteen or fifteen years? At least, it felt that long to me.”

"It did not feel that long to me… though it explains how you could do everything swiftly and perfectly, from my point of view,” Jake said. “But how about the fact that the First Sage saw me there? Could even see things about me? That is not normal.”

"I tend to not comment on things I have limited understanding of. The problem isn’t that there is no explanation of what it means, but that there are too many explanations. You peer at a Record Fragment, right? This means you cannot alter the fragments, only view them. I don’t subscribe to your theory of predetermination, but more to the theory that the world you see is the same world from back then. It is a mirror of it. If it is a simulation like the Seat of the Exalted Prima event, or maybe the skill even creates a second true universe with a split timeline or something else insane like that upon you being seen, I have no way of knowing.”

The Viper shook his head, then continued, "Let me say it like this. There are other skills to see certain Records, or there have at least been prior system events where it happens. Tell me, have you ever felt someone observing you? Besides me, of course. I am talking about if you have ever felt like someone observed you the same way you observed me during your Path of the Heretic-Chosen."

"Not that I recall," Jake said with a deep frown. Yeah… Villy had a point. If Jake had been observed, he would have damn well noticed it. At least, he believed he would have. So the only explanation would be that no one had traveled back and looked at him. He saw a few reasons that could be. A: Jake never made it to godhood and was thus not worth looking at. B: He couldn’t notice if they were looking at him. C: No one would ever, in the history of infinity, get a skill or anything like that to observe his past the same way Jake could with Villy.

He called bullshit on all three of those. It was way more probable that these Record-peering skills just didn’t truly interfere with the past.

"You got a point. But even so, no comments on what he said? Something about my Origin… Also, the way the vision ended was so weird. Like it was forcefully stopped. I didn’t even feel the usual transportation out of the skill…”

"No comments indeed," Villy said. "It is your skill and your Origin. I am sure you have come across the word Origin before, so refer to that."

"Aight…" Jake relented.

He had come across the word Origin before, and he had a pretty good idea of what it was. Something to do with the core of a Truesoul, or perhaps the "true essence" of stuff. Okay, Jake had to admit, he was still a bit iffy on the details.

"Now," Villy said with a teasing smile, “you said you had something else you wanted my help with before you went on a mental journey? What can I do for my dear Chosen?"

Jake nodded, happy Villy had brought him back on track. "Yep. My simulacrum and I have been talking, and we will need some… time."

"You are asking for a time-dilated chamber?" the Viper asked with a raised eyebrow.

"That was the plan. Why, isn’t it possible? I know you said too much time dilation can fuck you up, and I did spend a long time learning about Shroud…"

"Jake, you spent less than fifteen years in time dilation while in D-grade. That is well below average for people like you. As long as you don’t plan on actually fighting or doing any crafting, I see no issues with it. Will it primarily be meditation?"

"And a bit of light practice, maybe, but yeah, it will just be me and myself," Jake confirmed.

"In that case, sure." Villy shrugged. "Though I do have to point out the absurdity of asking me for a time-dilated chamber personally when the Order already offers them for its members."

Jake… did not know that.

"Well, you know, I want the best of the best,” Jake joked. “Top-of-the-line time chambers only.”

"I doubt Aeon can be arsed to come by."

"I guess the second-best is acceptable, too." Jake grinned.

"Acceptable compliment. Wanna go right away?"

"May as well," Jake said. "Though I have no idea how long it will take."

"Nor do I know how much I can crank the time magic." Villy grinned back, almost a bit too giddy.